<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-03-16T05:41:35-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MiningSoft</title><subtitle>Miners developer</subtitle><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Cryptocurrency Explained - What is It, Types, Pros &amp;amp; Cons [2023]</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/cryptocurrency/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cryptocurrency Explained - What is It, Types, Pros &amp;amp; Cons [2023]" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/cryptocurrency</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/cryptocurrency/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper btc">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      Learn all about the potential of cryptocurrency and what it means for the future.
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>This article breaks down what it is, how it works, what types of cryptocurrency exist, the pros and cons, and use cases. Learn the basics and understand cryptocurrency simply!</em></p>

<h2 id="definition">Definition</h2>

<p>Cryptocurrencies are encrypted digital currencies that are created and stored electronically. They can be spent like regular money, but can also be used to buy and sell other digital currencies.</p>

<p>Virtual money has no material equivalent and is a record in a special <a href="/en/articles/blockchain/">database (blockchain)</a>. The base is very reliable, and the technology built on it, perhaps, gives humanity even more value than the coin itself.</p>

<!-- adunit 1 -->

<div id="cryptox-ad-20003805-10905748"></div>

<!-- adunit 2 -->
<div id="cryptox-ad-20003718-10905748"></div>

<!-- adunit 3 -->
<div id="cryptox-ad-20003615-10905748"></div>

<script>
	const cxjs = new CryptoX_SDK();
	const adUnits = [
		{
			slot: 'cryptox-ad-20003805-10905748',
			placementId: '20003805',
			appId: '10905748',
			size: [728, 90]
		},
		{
			slot: 'cryptox-ad-20003718-10905748',
			placementId: '20003718',
			appId: '10905748',
			size: [300, 250]
		},
		{
			slot: 'cryptox-ad-20003615-10905748',
			placementId: '20003615',
			appId: '10905748',
			size: [300, 250]
		},
		// other ad unit...
	];
	if ('display' in cxjs) {
		cxjs.display(adUnits);
	}
</script>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/what_is_crypto_simple.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/what_is_crypto_simple.webp" alt="cryptocurrency in simple terms" />
<figcaption>How do you explain cryptocurrency to a beginner?</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Simply put, cryptocurrency is digital money created from code using <a href="/en/articles/mining/">mining</a> farms or validators. The balances of the owners are stored in the ledger (register), which is distributed on many independent computers. This means that the blockchain registry does not belong to one person or organization, but exists as a complete copy on a large number of devices.</p>

<p class="notice--success">When a new transaction is made, it is verified by <strong>every</strong> <a href="/en/articles/blockchain/">computer in the blockchain network</a> and then validated. This makes any falsification almost impossible.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_explained.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_explained.webp" alt="Definition &amp; Meaning" />
<figcaption>Definition.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p><i class="fab fa-bitcoin"></i> <span class="bold">Is there a physical cryptocurrency?</span><br />
Think of cryptocurrency like owning a piece of land. You may not physically own it, but your ownership is recorded in the local government ledger. In the event of a dispute, you can enter your name on the ledger as the registered owner to prove that you bought and own the land.</p>

<p>Only in the case of digital assets, you do not need to confirm the ownership in the local government or in the bank.</p>

<p class="notice--warning">Decentralization rules everything here, not banks.</p>

<h2 id="important-terms-and-brief-explanations">Important terms and brief explanations</h2>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<p>What does <span class="yel">decentralized</span> cryptocurrency mean?</p>

<dl>
  <dt>Decentralization</dt>
  <dd>With decentralization, no one person or group has control - instead, <strong>all users collectively retain control</strong>. Decentralized blockchains are immutable. This means that the entered data is irreversible.</dd>
  <dt>Decentralized</dt>
  <dd>The term means that the decision is made at different nodes. Each node determines its behavior, which ultimately affects the behavior of the entire system. This ensures that no node has complete system information.</dd>
</dl>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_decentralization.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_decentralization.webp" alt="What is Decentralization in Blockchain" />
<figcaption>Decentralization.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Cryptocurrencies are actively implementing decentralized and distributed systems in their favor. All popular digital assets have these characteristics.</p>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="principle-of-operation">Principle of operation</h2>

<div class="notice--success">
  <p><em>Main article: <strong><a href="/en/articles/blockchain/">How Blockchain Works in Cryptocurrency and Other Industries</a></strong></em></p>
</div>
<hr />

<p>Let’s take a look at how cryptocurrencies work. Digital currencies run on the blockchain. It makes transactions with virtual currencies especially secure. You can think of it as a log containing every cryptocurrency transaction. To protect against attacks, transaction data is distributed decentralized across multiple computers (nodes) that form a peer-to-peer network.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_how_works.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_how_works.webp" alt="How does cryptocurrency work" />
<figcaption>How it works.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Several transactions are combined into an encrypted data block. If it is full, it closes and can no longer be changed. Block by block, a chain is created that exists in the same way on all computers on the network. If someone tries to manipulate the chain on one of the computers, they will be blocked.</p>

<h3 id="mining-how-blocks-are-added-to-a-blockchain">Mining: how blocks are added to a blockchain</h3>

<div class="notice--success">
  <p><em>Main article: <strong><a href="/en/articles/mining/">How mining works</a></strong></em></p>
</div>
<hr />

<p>To process, secure and synchronize the growing number of transactions on the network requires huge computing power. If you lend your computing power to this “mining” process, you will be rewarded with coins. However, mining consumes a huge amount of electricity - as much as the Netherlands in a year.</p>

<p>New coins are generated in the process of mining, i.e., deciphering the tasks for issuing coins.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_mining.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_mining.webp" alt="Mining explained" />
<figcaption>Mining.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>In this way, coins are created by a network of participating users (miners). They are needed to decrypt cryptographic tasks for issuing tokens and coins.</p>

<p>Transactions in progress are checked for validity by thousands of computers on the network, verified and stored in a decentralized manner.</p>

<h2 id="usage">Usage</h2>

<p>Cryptocurrencies are designed to operate as independent, decentralized and cryptographically encrypted payment systems. The goal is to create better and more secure means of payment. Unlike official currencies, most cryptocurrencies are decentralized and usually limited in number. Some of them can also be used anonymously.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_used.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_used.webp" alt="Uses of cryptocurrency" />
<figcaption>What is a cryptocurrency for?</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Cryptocurrency is needed for:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Access to personal finance,</li>
  <li>conclusion of smart contracts,<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></li>
  <li>use of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things">Internet of things</a>,</li>
  <li>digitization of metals,</li>
  <li><a href="/en/guide/usdt-works/">stablecoins</a>,</li>
  <li>crypto money can be traded on special <a href="https://bytwork.com/en/markets">exchanges or through crypto brokers</a>.</li>
</ul>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_use_cases.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_use_cases.webp" alt="Cryptocurrency application" />
<figcaption>Application of cryptocurrency.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--danger">In general, the use of cryptocurrencies as a means of payment is declining and banned in some countries.</p>

<p>Several companies accept payment with bitcoins. In most cases, online payment is accepted. Restaurants, cafes and shops are the exception rather than the rule. To be able to pay at the checkout, a corresponding QR code is usually required.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Cryptocurrency in 5 minutes - explain crypto to complete beginners</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT5M33S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2021-06-29T15:30:00Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/1YyAzVmP9xQ/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="736225" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/1YyAzVmP9xQ" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="1YyAzVmP9xQ"></div>
<span itemprop="description">This video on Cryptocurrency covers all the important concepts from basics to advanced.</span>
</div>

<h2 id="types">Types</h2>

<div class="notice--success">
  <p><em>Main article: <strong><a href="/en/articles/bitcoin/">How Bitcoin works</a></strong></em></p>
</div>
<hr />

<p>Bitcoin is the most famous of the virtual currencies. Since it was developed in 2009, its cost has skyrocketed. If you had bought Bitcoins for little money then, you would be a millionaire today.<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<section class="imp">
  <p><span class="par"><i class="fas fa-mug-hot"></i> <span class="bold">What are all the different types of cryptocurrency?</span> <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <span class="yel bold">Classic cryptocurrencies</span> on the blockchain that change their value as a result of the interaction of supply and demand . Examples: bitcoin, ethereum. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <span class="yel bold">Stable coins</span> with a certain fixed value - the rates never change here. For example, <a href="/en/guide/usdt-works/">Tether USDT</a>. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <span class="yel bold">Tokens</span> - coins that do not have their own blockchain. They exist as part of an ecosystem of another network. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <span class="yel bold">Meme coins</span> - comedians of the crypto world. These coins are gaining popularity thanks to memes and social networks.<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup><br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <span class="yel bold">Alternative</span> coins (altcoins).<br /></span></p>

</section>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_tokens.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_tokens.webp" alt="Token and cryptocurrency differences." />
<figcaption>Difference between coins and tokens.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h3 id="altcoins">Altcoins</h3>

<p>Contrary to what the name might suggest, altcoin is not one single cryptocurrency that bears that name. The “ALT” part of the word does not refer to any one new virtual currency such as “BIT” in Bitcoin. The word “alto” comes from the word “alternative”.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">Altcoin refers to all cryptocurrencies developed <em>after</em> bitcoin.</p>

<p>Thus, altcoin is an alternative to the first digital currency. For example, Ethereum is considered an altcoin.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_altcoins.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_altcoins.webp" alt="Altcoin Explained" />
<figcaption>What is an altcoin.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Cryptocurrency can be called an altcoin only if certain requirements are met, which BTC also has. This requirement is simply called: blockchain. Only cryptocurrencies that are also based on the same technology as Bitcoin can also be called an alternative to Bitcoin.</p>

<p>This point is important for distinguishing an altcoin from a cryptocurrency.</p>

<h3 id="promising">Promising</h3>

<p>In the years since the first bitcoin transaction in 2009, <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/">thousands of additional cryptocurrencies</a> have emerged, creating a confusing environment for investors. Some of these altcoins feature major technical innovations that set them apart from Bitcoin, while others have simply become popular digital currency brands and social media memes.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">Cryptocurrency investing remains highly speculative, but it can be highly lucrative for investors willing to take risks in the hope of big payouts.<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup></p>

<h4 id="ethereum-eth">Ethereum (ETH)</h4>

<p>The next major digital currency after Bitcoin is Ether. On the Ethereum network, you can enter into smart contracts, that is, digital contracts that come into force after the contractual agreement is fully fulfilled.</p>

<ul>
  <li>On the market since 2015.</li>
  <li>Much more environmentally friendly due to the update <a href="/en/guide/merge/">Ethereum 2.0.</a></li>
  <li>Uses its own blockchain.</li>
  <li>Traded as the leading currency after bitcoin.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="ripple-xrp">Ripple (XRP)</h4>

<p>Banks love this cryptocurrency because the payment network works with them and speeds up international bank transfers. Mining is not required - all coins have already been generated. There are 100 billion XRP in total.</p>

<ul>
  <li>On the market since 2012.</li>
  <li>Considered a classic bridge currency.</li>
  <li>Price fluctuations in the cent range.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="litecoin-ltc">Litecoin (LTC)</h4>

<p>Bitcoin’s little brother, the efficient Litecoin blockchain can generate more blocks and therefore process more transactions in less time.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_btc_altcoins.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_btc_altcoins.webp" alt="best altcoins" />
<figcaption>Promising and popular altcoins.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h4 id="iota">IOTA</h4>

<p>This network is designed for IoT applications <a href="https://www.kaspersky.com/resource-center/definitions/what-is-iot">(Internet of Things)</a> and allows transactions between machines or devices. In the future, you can use it, for example, to pay for charging an electric car or to protect e-health data. There are many large companies on the side of IOTA. Instead of a blockchain, there are nodes and a graph system. The project becomes faster and more secure with every connected user.</p>

<h4 id="cardano-ada">Cardano (ADA)</h4>

<p>The network wants to fix the first problems of other cryptocurrencies by combining their advantages. The project is easier to scale, conduct faster transactions and provide even greater security.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Created in 2015 by the co-founder of Ethereum.</li>
  <li>More focus on sustainability and interoperability.</li>
  <li>Any scalability.</li>
  <li>Encryption.</li>
  <li>Considered a new generation of cryptocurrencies.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p class="notice--info">Sometimes you can hear that some altcoins are called tokens. In this case, the term is correct if the altcoin is built on the platform of another coin. For example, tokens <a href="/en/guide/usdt-works/">Tether (USDT)</a>, USD Coin (USDC) or SHIBA INU (SHIB) exist on the Ethereum platform.</p>

<h3 id="tokens">Tokens</h3>

<p>It is not easy for beginners to recognize the difference between cryptocurrencies and tokens. Tokens are digital assets that are embedded on <em>other</em> blockchains and do not have their own blockchain to run and operate. For example, many of the most popular tokens in the crypto space are built on the Ethereum blockchain and are often referred to as ERC-20 tokens.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_tokens_vs_coins.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_tokens_vs_coins.webp" alt="Crypto Coins vs Tokens" />
<figcaption>Differences between tokens and cryptocurrencies</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Tokens can represent an asset, such as digital art, or provide the holder with a specific service or application access.</p>

<p><strong>Nft tokens</strong></p>

<p>NFT (English non-fungible token - “non-fungible token”), also a unique token, is a digital entity that represents a specific physical or virtual object in the blockchain, which makes it unique. You can think of it as a painting by a famous artist. No matter how many copies or reprints there are, the original is always unique.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_nft.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_nft.webp" alt="what are Nft tokens" />
<figcaption>What are NFTs and how do they work.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>As digital proofs of authenticity, NFTs can display any virtual or real object on the blockchain.</p>

<p class="notice--primary">NFTs are best known for the hype surrounding digital art such as GIFs and memes. A reworked version of the popular cat cartoon “Nyan Cat” has been auctioned for the equivalent of around 500,000 euros.<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></p>

<h3 id="meme-coins">Meme coins</h3>

<p>Meme coins are cryptocurrencies based on a meme - an Internet joke that has become popular. It doesn’t have a purpose behind it like bitcoin wants to make the global financial system fairer.<sup id="fnref:6" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote" rel="footnote">6</a></sup> They were made for fun.</p>

<p>Memecoins are a group of cryptocurrencies that have no intrinsic utility or function, but simply act as a kind of <span class="yel">funny currency</span>. The first meme coin was Dogecoin, which started as a parody of Bitcoin. Many investors showed great interest in the fun currency, and over time, the price has risen significantly.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_meme_tokens.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_meme_tokens.webp" alt="What is coin meme" />
<figcaption>What is a Memes Tokens.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h3 id="stablecoins">Stablecoins</h3>

<p>A stablecoin is a cryptocurrency whose value is pegged to the price of another asset, hence the term “stable”. For example, a dollar-pegged stablecoin should always be valued at 1 USD if it functions properly.<sup id="fnref:7" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote" rel="footnote">7</a></sup></p>

<p><a href="/en/guide/usdt-works/">Tether</a> is a classic example of a stablecoin. The rate remains always stable one to one to the dollar. The circulation is controlled by the company issuing it - Tether Limited and the Bitfinex exchange.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_stablecoins.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_stablecoins.webp" alt="what are stablecoins" />
<figcaption>Stablecoins: definition, how they work, and types</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The table provides comparisons of stablecoins with digital assets.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Cryptocurrencies</th>
      <th>Stablecoins</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Traded algorithmically and without reference to any other currency</td>
      <td>All stablecoins are always pegged to different assets (fiat currencies, commodities, etc.).</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Great growth opportunities</td>
      <td>Lower volatility to trade and store value</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>High volatility</td>
      <td>Suitable for hedging crypto profits</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>High risk of losing everything</td>
      <td>Cheap money transfers abroad are possible</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td> </td>
      <td>Better accumulate interest</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td> </td>
      <td>No Growth Opportunities Like Traditional Crypto Assets</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="comparison-with-fiat-money">Comparison with fiat money</h2>

<p>Fiat currencies, also “Cash” are traditional, paper money that everyone is used to. These currencies are only valuable because the regulators say so, and because the people who use them still believe in their value. Fiat money like dollars can be used to exchange for goods and services.</p>

<p>Let’s compare fiat currencies and digital ones.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_vs_fiat.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_vs_fiat.webp" alt="cryptocurrencies vs fiat currencies" />
<figcaption>Comparing cryptocurrency to fiat money</figcaption></a></figure>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Cryptocurrencies</th>
      <th>Fiat currencies</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Brand new</td>
      <td>Well established</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Can be used anonymously</td>
      <td>Not anonymous</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Have no limits of use</td>
      <td>Limited by borders</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Without inflation (limited release)</td>
      <td>Subject to inflation</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="advantages">Advantages</h2>

<p>Cryptocurrencies, and even more so blockchain technology, can lead to improvements at a fundamental level with the approach to decentralization in various economic and social areas. As a result, entire sectors of the economy can be turned inside out in the long run. Traditional systems will no longer be needed.</p>

<p>The main advantages are the storage and transport of all information in a tamper-proof and fault-tolerant manner.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_potencial.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_potencial.webp" alt="cryptocurrencies Advantages" />
<figcaption>The Benefits of Digital Assets</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="disadvantages">Disadvantages</h2>

<p>In addition to the numerous advantages of cryptocurrencies, the risks cannot be neglected. Moreover, a beginner in the crypto world needs to carefully understand both the advantages and disadvantages.</p>

<p>The following theses are usually attributed to the disadvantages of cryptocurrencies:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Low liquidity compared to traditional financial instruments.</li>
  <li>Strong price fluctuations.</li>
  <li>Possible total loss of funds or data.</li>
  <li>Due to the lack of regulatory mechanisms, there are no guarantees for the safety of electronic crypto wallets.</li>
  <li>Loss of a password to an electronic crypto wallet or its inoperability leads to the irretrievable loss of all coins.</li>
</ul>

<p class="notice--danger">The developers of some digital assets are partially unknown and are engaged in deceiving users. You should be attentive to the crypto project, study it.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_disadvantages.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_disadvantages.webp" alt="Cons of Cryptocurrencies" />
<figcaption>Top 5 disadvantages of cryptocurrency</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="risks">Risks</h2>

<p>A serious risk to consider is that billions of dollars worth of digital assets have been stolen from cryptocurrency exchanges over the past few years.<sup id="fnref:8" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote" rel="footnote">8</a></sup></p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_risks.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_risks.webp" alt="Cryptocurrency risks" />
<figcaption>Risks</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Therefore, it is extremely important to beware of unlicensed platforms and only buy cryptocurrency from a regulated exchange or broker, of which there are not many. If you want to store your <a href="/en/wallets/">cryptocurrencies in your own wallet</a>, there are fewer risks.</p>

<p>It is possible to unequivocally answer the question: is cryptocurrency good or bad by summing up the advantages and risks.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Features / benefits</th>
      <th>Risks / disadvantages</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Decentralization</td>
      <td>Volatility</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Transparency of all operations</td>
      <td>No clear regulation</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Flexibility in use cases</td>
      <td>Often there is no real solution to the problem</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Protection against unauthorized access</td>
      <td>High consumption of resources and energy</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Despite the disadvantages and risks, you should not hope for the collapse of cryptocurrencies.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Bitcoin, however, will not disappear because it is in fact decentralized and is still in high demand as a replacement for obsolete money by individuals, corporations and nation states.”
<sup>- Samson Mou, CEO, JAN3</sup></p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="law-bans-and-adoption">Law: bans and adoption</h2>

<p>Regulation in most countries, which is mostly just beginning, is a risk that should not be underestimated when investing.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">In addition to supporters, there are a number of opponents of cryptocurrencies. States like El Salvador feel their chance to become more independent of the dollar. Other states, such as China, are fiddling with their own digital money and have driven mining out of the country and banned trade.<sup id="fnref:9" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:9" class="footnote" rel="footnote">9</a></sup></p>

<p>The amount of energy or computing power required for mining, including the required hardware, and the high energy consumption of each transaction is a thorn in the side of many government officials around the world.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_legal.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_legal.webp" alt="regulation of cryptocurrencies in countries" />
<figcaption>Countries that have banned or restricted the circulation of cryptocurrencies</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--success">On the other hand, there are supporters who see digital assets as a great opportunity for their country and are determined to follow this trend so as not to miss the stage of technological development, as was the case with the Internet and the so-called FANG shares. (Facebook, Amazon, Netflix, Google).</p>

<p>Even among supporters, the picture is divided. Some see more regulation as a positive thing, as it will build confidence. The other side insists on decentralization and anonymity at all costs.</p>

<p>A general and worldwide ban is in doubt. Partial regulation is likely to have a negative impact on the whole situation, at least in the short term, but then may clear the way for institutional investors and thus pave the way for the very broad masses.</p>

<p>Therefore, a definitive declaration of a general ban is not possible.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-crypto-backed-by">What Is crypto Backed By?</h2>

<p>Cryptocurrencies are not backed by real assets or tangible securities. They are traded between the parties by agreement without a broker and tracked in digital ledgers.<sup id="fnref:10" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:10" class="footnote" rel="footnote">10</a></sup> The rate is not backed by anything other than actual supply and demand.</p>

<p>At the same time, the cryptocurrency is provided by the value that the users of the Network give for it, reliability, limited emission and a number of other factors. According to many analysts, they have an even greater impact on the stability of the monetary system than gold and foreign exchange reserves.</p>

<h2 id="what-determines-price">What Determines Price?</h2>

<p>As a general rule, if the stock market crashes, then the cryptocurrency market crashes with it. There are also influencing factors, such as the legal regulation of cryptocurrencies, which is still largely open.</p>

<p class="notice--success">The reasons vary, but it’s still worth taking a look at <a href="https://bytwork.com/en/articles/btc-chart-history">Bitcoin’s price history since its inception and cycles</a> of the huge ups and downs that accompanied it.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/history_price_btc.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/history_price_btc.webp" alt=" all-time Bitcoin price chart" />
<figcaption>Bitcoin price history</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Sometimes there are sharp and unpredictable price fluctuations. It is impossible to say why the rates rise or fall. This represents a potential risk for investors. Due to the high volatility, investors are quicker to sell these high-risk investments.</p>

<h2 id="how-does-crypto-make-money">How does crypto make money?</h2>

<p>Cryptocurrencies allow you to earn money in various ways:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Trading speculation in cryptocurrencies or CFD contracts.</li>
  <li>“Reward” for doing various work on the network</li>
  <li>“Winning”</li>
  <li>Crypto lending and staking</li>
  <li>Investment</li>
  <li>Airdrops and forks</li>
  <li>Mining</li>
</ol>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_earn.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_earn.webp" alt="Cryptocurrency options" />
<figcaption>Cryptocurrency earning options</figcaption></a></figure>

<h3 id="trading">Trading</h3>

<p>If you buy cryptocurrencies and the price rises, you can sell them and make a profit. It sounds very simple. However, for beginners it is important that theymore thoroughly dealt with cryptocurrencies. For example, not all digital currencies are equally suitable for trading and earning.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_trade.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/cryptocurrency/en/cryptocurrency_trade.webp" alt="Trading" />
<figcaption>Trading options</figcaption></a></figure>

<p><span class="bold">Contract Trading (CFD)</span></p>

<p>It is important to decide in advance whether you want to buy cryptocurrencies or want to trade CFDs without buying cryptocurrencies yourself.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">Contracts for difference (CFDs) are derivatives that allow you to bet on how the price will develop. CFDs exist on stocks and other real assets, as well as cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">Remember that CFDs are very risky. Depending on what price action the bet is on, whether the price goes down or up, you can make a mistake and lose.</p>

<h3 id="crypto-lending">Crypto lending</h3>

<p>Crypto lending offers the opportunity to earn interest by lending your cryptocurrencies. This can be done on peer-to-peer lending platforms, some crypto exchanges, and through so-called <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/defi/">DeFi, decentralized financial applications</a>, among others.</p>

<h3 id="investing">Investing</h3>

<p>Investing is a long-term strategy for buying and holding crypto assets for a long time. Cryptocurrency assets are usually well suited for a buy and hold strategy. They are extremely volatile in the short term but have huge upside potential in the long term.</p>

<h3 id="staking">Staking</h3>

<p>Simply put, <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking/">staking</a> is like a bank deposit with interest. The user transfers funds to the account, stores them and receives passive income for this. The more funds in the account, the higher the earnings. However, the more participants, the less income.</p>

<h3 id="mining">Mining</h3>

<p>Crypto coins are generated in a <a href="/en/articles/mining/">process called mining</a>. This process is complicated, but in simple terms, mining means that computers solve mathematical equations and receive bitcoins or other cryptocurrencies as a reward.<sup id="fnref:11" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:11" class="footnote" rel="footnote">11</a></sup></p>

<h3 id="airdrops-and-forks">Airdrops and forks</h3>

<p>An airdrop is a process by which a company distributes its tokens to the wallets of specific users, completely free of charge, in order to stimulate brand awareness.</p>

<p class="notice--success">Why would companies just give away their tokens? This is an effective way to get fast network usage and create hype around new blockchain based business. This acts as a way to reward investors and clients.</p>

<p>Some companies may use Airdrops for technological reasons, such as for a hard fork.</p>

<p>A hard fork occurs when changes are made to the code that create two paths for a project to develop. This is exactly what happened with Bitcoin Cash (BCH). After the fork, all BTC holders received BCH.</p>

<h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h2>

<p>To sum it up, it is important to do a thorough research, both in terms of the cryptocurrency you plan to add to your portfolio, and in terms of the exchange or broker you are opening an account with.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">Cryptocurrencies are not a form of investment with safe interest rates. Still, earning on cryptocurrency is possible. If you are willing to take on a high risk with this type of investment.</p>

<p>Cryptocurrencies are an incredibly exciting trend that is no longer a dream of the future. Large profits are possible, but extensive knowledge of the financial market and investments is required.</p>

<p>Before diving into the crypto adventure, you should collect a lot of information, which is also described on the MiningSoft.org resource. Then you are more likely to celebrate successes rather than mourn losses.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">How Cryptocurrency actually works. How are cryptocurrencies created?</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT25M16S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2017-07-07T16:51:37Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bBC-nXj3Ng4/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="14562173" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/bBC-nXj3Ng4" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="bBC-nXj3Ng4"></div>
<span itemprop="description">All your questions about Cryptocurrency answered.</span>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Crypto: The World’s Greatest Scam?</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT54M19S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2023-01-01T15:00:16Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ORdWE_ffirg/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="2094462" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/ORdWE_ffirg" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="ORdWE_ffirg"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Bitcoin to Blockchains, to NFTs, to Web 3.0... it's time to find out if it's really all the hype or just part of one of the greatest scams in human history. </span>
</div>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smart_contract">Smart contract: concept, legal nature, features of conclusion and execution</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/people/083016/who-are-top-5-bitcoin-millionaires.asp">Who Are the Top Bitcoin Millionaires?</a> <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/investing/cryptocurrency/different-types-of-cryptocurrencies/">Different Types of Cryptocurrencies – Forbes Advisor</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://money.usnews.com/investing/stock-market-news/slideshows/best-altcoins-to-buy">The Best Altcoins to Buy - Investing - U.S. News</a> <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/02/19/nyan-cat-nft-sells-for-300-eth-opening-door-to-the-meme-economy/">Nyan Cat NFT Sells for 300 ETH, Opening Door to the ‘Meme Economy’ - CoinDesk</a> <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:6" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://bytwork.com/articles/mem-tokeny">What is a meme token? Dogecoin, Shibu Inu. Why are they popular?</a> <a href="#fnref:6" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:7" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/investing/cryptocurrency/stablecoins/">What Are Stablecoins? – Forbes Advisor</a> <a href="#fnref:7" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:8" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://bytwork.com/en/articles/bitcoin-theft">Bitcoin theft: TOP 50 biggest thefts on exchanges [2011-2023]</a> <a href="#fnref:8" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:9" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.thomsonreuters.com/en-us/posts/wp-content/uploads/sites/20/2022/04/Cryptos-Report-Compendium-2022.pdf">Thomson Reuters 2023</a> <a href="#fnref:9" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:10" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/cryptocurrency-4427699">Investing in cryptocurrency</a> <a href="#fnref:10" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:11" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://bitcoin.org/en/how-it-works">How does Bitcoin work?</a> <a href="#fnref:11" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn all about the potential of cryptocurrency and what it means for the future. This article breaks down what it is, how it works, what types of cryptocurrency exist, the pros and cons, and use cases. Learn the basics and understand cryptocurrency simply!]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">What is banned content in Russia? (Censorship)</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/blog/rkn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is banned content in Russia? (Censorship)" /><published>2023-02-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/blog/rkn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/blog/rkn/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper wallet">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
     Roskomnadzor censorship on the example of bitcoin.
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>In this article, you will learn about government blocking and how to solve this problem.</em></p>

<p>In August 2022, the largest website about cryptocurrencies, mining and blockchain - <a href="https://bytwork.com/en/">bytwork.com</a> was blocked by the Roskomnadzor (RKN), the Federal Service for Supervision of Communications, Information Technology and Mass Media.</p>

<p><strong>Legal</strong>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The basis for inclusion in the register of the information specified in paragraph 2 of this article is, among other things, a court decision that has entered into force on recognizing information disseminated via the Internet as information whose distribution is prohibited in the Russian Federation (paragraph 2 Part 5, Article 15.1 of Federal Law No. 149-FZ).<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>In plain language, the basis for blocking was information about Bitcoin and its acquisition.</p>

<p><em>The essence of the blocking</em>: in 2020, the Onega City Court ruled to block the site bytwork.com without notifying the site administrators about the court, although there was such a possibility (the mail was indicated in the site footer).</p>

<p class="notice--warning">For 2 years (from 2020 to 2022), the matter went to Roskomnadzor, and only in August 2022 the department blocked the site.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Received a notification from representatives of the department:</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/blog/rkn/uvedomlenie_rkn.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/blog/rkn/uvedomlenie_rkn.webp" alt=" notification" /></a></figure>

<p>The government notice proposes to remove material allegedly infringing the law. Otherwise, it will be included in the list of prohibited information.</p>

<h2 id="what-to-do-after-blocking">What to do after blocking?</h2>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<p>The Bytwork team initially tried to handle the whole process on their own. They removed the page because of which there was a court and notified representatives of the department about it.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">However, Roskomnadzor considered that the entire domain is subject to blocking. And despite the fact that the administrators of the Bytwork site removed the page against which the judgment was issued, <strong>RKN left the entire domain blocked</strong>.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/blog/rkn/rkn_block.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/blog/rkn/rkn_block.webp" alt="Roskomnadzor blocking" /><figcaption>Block type: entire domain, not article.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Next, Bytwork turned to lawyers. Not all lawyers understand how to conduct such cases, moreover, many did not understand what blocking from the RKN is and who blocks access to sites in Russia?</p>

<p>The Bytwork team realized that it was necessary to look for lawyers specializing in such cases!</p>

<p>According to numerous reviews and advice from administrators and owners of other sites-colleagues, the company DRC.law was found.</p>

<p><a href="https://drc.law/">DRC.law</a> is a large company of IT lawyers. They solve all legal issues for users, website owners, IT and Telecom businesses!</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/blog/rkn/drc.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/blog/rkn/drc.webp" alt=" DRC.law" /></a></figure>

<p>Contacting <a href="https://drc.law/">DRC.law</a>, Bytwork immediately outlined the issue. The lawyers instantly, thanks to their vast experience in handling such cases, described a possible solution to the blocking problem, drew up an action plan and honestly set the deadlines (let’s say right away that DRC.law did everything quickly and efficiently, all the deadlines depended only on the Court, post offices and other related to this).</p>

<p>After listening to the action plan, the Bytwork team decided to cooperate with DRC.law.</p>

<h2 id="solution">Solution</h2>

<p>The DRC.law team immediately proceeded to create an appeal based on the fact that Bytwork was not notified of the trial and the procedural deadlines were violated.</p>

<p>It should be noted right away that DRC.law gives you a choice of 2 options for working with them:<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<ol>
  <li>You personally go to court with lawyers;</li>
  <li>You draw up a power of attorney for the company (it is only for the court), and the lawyer himself goes to court on your behalf. Bytwork chose option 2!</li>
</ol>

<p>Since the court was very far away, it was easier and more profitable to issue a power of attorney.</p>

<p>After the appeal was drawn up, it was sent to court (everything was done very quickly). The appeal was sent in <strong>August 2022</strong>! And the answer from the Onega City Court came already <strong>October 10, 2022</strong>.</p>

<p>Note that the letter came to the Bytwork team at the specified home address and in parallel to the legal address drc.law.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/blog/rkn/appelyacia.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/blog/rkn/appelyacia.webp" alt=" Appeal to Roskomnadzor" /><figcaption>Notice that the state has accepted the appeal.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--primary">Further, only <strong>November 1, 2022</strong> the case goes to court!</p>

<p>The appeal was considered for about 2 months, after which the date of the new hearing was set for <strong>12/21/2022</strong>!</p>

<h3 id="second-hearing">Second hearing?</h3>

<p>On December 1, 2022, right before the new year, the Bytwork team gets a great message from the lawyers:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Hello! The lawyer wrote that the decision of the Onega city court was canceled in the part of the bytwork website and the case was sent for a new trial to the court of first instance. Next, we are waiting for the case to be sent to the court of first instance and the appointment of a court session.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>AND:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“An important point, at this stage, after receiving the appealsionic determination, we can submit a request to the RKN and the site will be unblocked “</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Everything is great, and we are very grateful to drc.law for the work done, but the matter is still not fully resolved, because:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“However, the case is not closed, because the issue of blocking depends on the second session of the first instance”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So, the new hearing will take place on February 3, 2023!</p>

<p class="notice--ya">But until that moment, lawyers from <a href="https://drc.law/">DRC.law</a> wrote a letter to the RKN to unblock the site (since the case in which we were blocked by the RKN no longer existed). And thanks to their letter to Roskomnadzor on January 23, bytwork.com was already unblocked!</p>

<h3 id="victory">Victory!</h3>

<p>On February 3, 2023, the Bytwork team receives the following letter from attorneys:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Hello! I have great news: during the meeting after the break, the prosecutor announced that he was dropping his claim regarding the requirements for bytwork. The refusal was accepted by the court, the proceedings were terminated. So everything ended well.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>That’s all! The Bytwork team won the case thanks to the lawyers from drc.law! They advised and accompanied Bytwork throughout the case!</p>

<p>Huge thanks to:</p>

<p>Inna Tverezovskaya.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/blog/rkn/urist_1.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/blog/rkn/urist_1.webp" alt=" Lawyer Inna Tverezovskaya" /></a></figure>

<p>And Anna Kuznetsova</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/blog/rkn/urist_2.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/blog/rkn/urist_2.webp" alt=" Lawyer Anna Kuznetsova" /></a></figure>

<p>They handled our case and answered all our questions in detail!</p>

<h2 id="question-answering">Question Answering</h2>

<div class="schema-faq-code" itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/FAQPage">
     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">What should I do if the site is blocked by Roskomnadzor?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Submit an application to eliminate content violations to Roskomnadzor via <a href="https://77.rkn.gov.ru/p3852/p8958/">the official website of the department </a> or by writing a letter to zapret-info@rkn.gov.ru. Or just <a href="https://drc.law/">contact lawyers</a>.</p>
         </div>
     </div>

     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">What is banned content in Russia?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">All content that, in the opinion of the authorities, is contrary to local law. Roskomnadzor is directly involved in maintaining the Register of banned sites. It sends lists of prohibited resources to communication providers. If access to the site is restricted in Russia, equipment supplied by Roskomnadzor telecom operators will detect and block this request.</p>
         </div>
     </div>

     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">How does the government block websites?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Roskomnadzor enters a domain name, website IP address or address of a specific page into its registry - a “black list”. Data from this registry is regularly downloaded to their equipment by all Russian Internet providers. In this case, the agency is obliged to notify the domain administrator about the blocking.</p>
         </div>
     </div>

     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">list of things banned in Russia</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">On its own initiative, Roskomnadzor can block websites for the following reasons:
<ul>
<li>pornography;</li>
<li>information about how drugs are produced and consumed;</li>
<li>information about methods of suicide and calls for it;</li>
<li>illegal information about violations against children;</li>
<li>information about illegal gambling;</li>
<li>information on how to buy alcohol and drugs remotely;</li>
<li>information harmful to children.</li>
</ul></p><p>Source: <a href="https://rkn.gov.ru/treatments/p459/p750/">Bases for blocking web pages</a>.</p>
         </div>
     </div>

     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">How do you check which websites are blocked?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">You can check the blocking through <a href="https://blocklist.rkn.gov.ru/">a form on the department's official website</a>.</p>
         </div>
     </div>

     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">List of websites blocked in Russia</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Website <a href="https://reestr.rublacklist.net/ru/">Roskomsvoboda maintains its own register</a> of blocked websites. </p>
         </div>
     </div>

     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">What is the procedure for blocking sites?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">
<ul>
<li>Applying requests. Roskomnadzor, as the operator of the registry of prohibited sites, accepts requests from citizens about resources containing prohibited information. ...</li>
<li>Submission of the application to the authorized body. ...</li>
<li>Consideration of the application by the authorized body. ...</li>
<li>Making an entry in the registry. ...</li>
<li>Check and block.</li>
</ul>
</p>
         </div>
     </div>
</div>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://onegasud--arh.sudrf.ru/modules.php?name=sud_delo&amp;srv_num=1&amp;name_op=doc&amp;number=122442559&amp;delo_id=41&amp;new=&amp;text_number=1">Administrative case decision</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://drc.law/uslugi/obzhalovanie-sudebnogo-resheniya-o-priznanii-informatsii-nezakonnoy/">Appeal against a court decision on declaring information illegal</a> <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roskomnadzor censorship on the example of bitcoin. In this article, you will learn about government blocking and how to solve this problem.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">What is Blockchain technology? In Simple Words (2023)</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/blockchain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Blockchain technology? In Simple Words (2023)" /><published>2023-02-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/blockchain/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper btc">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      Blockchain: what is it, how does it work and why is it needed?
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>A Simple Guide for the Newest of Beginners.</em></p>

<h2 id="what-is-blockchain">What is blockchain?</h2>

<p>Blockchain is a database that is not centrally located in one place, but distributed across many computers. The most important task of a blockchain is to securely document digital transactions. The technology has become famous thanks to cryptocurrencies such as <a href="/en/articles/bitcoin">bitcoin</a> and ethereum.</p>

<p>Simply put, a blockchain is a decentralized or distributed database (also: distributed ledger). This means that it does not reside with one person or organization, but exists as a complete copy on a large number of computers.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain.webp" alt="blockchain in simple terms" />
<figcaption>What is blockchain in simple words.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Blockchain was created as a cash book for the virtual currency Bitcoin, in which all users should be able to view all transactions. This technology is now being used for other cryptocurrencies as well.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_technology.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_technology.webp" alt="Technology Features" />
<figcaption>Technology features.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="important-terms-and-clear-explanations">Important terms and clear explanations</h2>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<dl>
  <dt>bitcoin</dt>
  <dd>Digital money designed for decentralized payments, that is, transactions without intermediaries such as banks.</dd>
  <dt>Cryptocurrency</dt>
  <dd>Bitcoin is also called a cryptocurrency. The Bitcoin payment system uses cryptographic methods to store the information it contains.</dd>
  <dt>Mining</dt>
  <dd>The process of mining cryptocurrency using the power of computers. They solve complex tasks by validating the blockchain network. At the same time, a new block of bitcoins is found, for which <a href="/en/articles/mining">miners</a> receive a reward.</dd>
</dl>

<p>As the name suggests, a blockchain is a <span class="yel">aggregation of blocks</span> of data. The easiest way to illustrate this approach is with an example. To do this, we use the Bitcoin cryptocurrency:</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/block.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/block.webp" alt="Blocks in blockchain" />
<figcaption>Blocks in the blockchain.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Simply put, a block of cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin or Ethereum can be compared to an Excel spreadsheet that has the following structure:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>User A (sender)</th>
      <th>User B (recipient)</th>
      <th>transaction amount</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>bc1ql2qw7ujlpn27hat32nklptsyytff30ys8wpj96</td>
      <td>bc1qhs3gptkxem5y7yaq2yg0un2m8hae6wt87gkx4n</td>
      <td>0.0518814 BTC</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>bc1qrpp7g75sx3ejclvsfdw2uahzchtyu7vumkuadu</td>
      <td>bc1q4s0vsp6gpc2aqt0cvd703hxy5jv93d76mra2mf</td>
      <td>0.0002813 BTC</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>The contents of the first two columns are the anonymous addresses (hash) of the sender and recipient of the corresponding transaction. With each transaction, the table (block) is supplemented with the next row. When a certain number of lines (size) is reached, the block is closed, sealed and filed. Then the next block starts.</p>

<p>Over time, numerous blocks are created that line up: the blockchain. The more blocks in the blockchain network, the higher the security. These blocks are created by miners.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_technology_simple.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_technology_simple.webp" alt="Explanation of blockchain technology blocks" />
<figcaption>Explanation of blocks of blockchain technology.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The big difference between a regular database and a blockchain is decentralized storage. The technology works with a network of computers and servers that store each individual block in parallel.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">How the blockchain is changing money and business. Don Tapscott</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT18M50S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2016-09-16T15:21:38Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Pl8OlkkwRpc/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="4928217" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/Pl8OlkkwRpc" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="Pl8OlkkwRpc"></div>
<span itemprop="description">What is the blockchain? If you don't know, you should; if you do, chances are you still need some clarification on how it actually works. Don Tapscott is here to help, demystifying this world-changing, trust-building technology which, he says, represents nothing less than the second generation of the internet and holds the potential to transform money, business, government and society.</span>
</div>

<p><span class="nev">Don Tapscott, Executive Chairman of the Blockchain Research Institute, is one of the world’s leading authorities on the impact of technology on business and society. <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> </span></p>

<h2 id="how-the-technology-works">How the technology works</h2>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Let’s explain using <a href="/en/articles/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> as an example. Think of blockchain as a ledger. Users of the Bitcoin cryptocurrency initiate transactions by buying, selling or paying with currency. As with an account, these movements must be recorded so that others can understand the transactions.</p>

<p>As a result, no one loses sight of how much Bitcoin has been bought and sold. Therefore, the computers involved create a block for transactions containing all the necessary information. The block is attached to the blockchain - the registry, expanding it. Computers encrypt the block using a complex algorithm.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_works.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_works.webp" alt="how blockchain works" />
<figcaption>How blockchain works.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Here is an example of how the technology works:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Buyer A buys bitcoins from buyer B.</li>
  <li>The blockchain network recognizes the booking and combines it with other cryptocurrency transactions into one block.</li>
  <li>All computers participating in the network now calculate the encryption algorithm.</li>
  <li>After the algorithm is generated, the computers coordinate and add the encrypted block to the block chain.</li>
  <li>All computers participating in the network keep the same block.</li>
  <li>Transaction completed.</li>
</ul>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">What Is Blockchain and How Does It Work? In 7 Minutes Explained</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT7M3S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2019-02-27T14:27:30Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/yubzJw0uiE4/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="1980795" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/yubzJw0uiE4" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="yubzJw0uiE4"></div>
<span itemprop="description">This Blockchain video will help you understand what led to the creation of Blockchain, what Blockchain is, how a Bitcoin transaction works, how Blockchain plays an integral role in it with feartures like hash encryption, proof of work and mining and how Blockchain technology is used in real life scenarios. Now, let’s dive into this video and understand the basics of Blockchain and How Blockchain works.</span>
</div>

<h2 id="application-implementation-in-business">Application, implementation in business</h2>

<p>Blockchain technology is the modern and best form of doing business. It removes layers of “bureaucracy” and friction.
Blockchain also eliminates the need for businesses that provide services related to checking and certifying goods, guarantees, and registering/recording a transaction in a public registry.</p>

<p>This means that all related jobs (accountants, sales representatives, lawyers, and other office administration workers) and businesses that have traditionally served these needs are a thing of the past.<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_use.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_use.webp" alt="blockchain use cases" />
<figcaption>blockchain use cases.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Blockchain can be applied to the following business areas:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Retail</li>
  <li>Transport</li>
  <li>Logistics</li>
  <li>Management</li>
  <li>Finance</li>
  <li>Services</li>
  <li>Banking</li>
  <li>Healthcare</li>
  <li>E-commerce</li>
  <li>Insurance</li>
  <li>Entertainment</li>
  <li>Energy</li>
  <li>Sports</li>
  <li>Real estate</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="which-business-will-kill-blockchain">Which business will kill blockchain</h3>

<p>Blockchain is needed where the speed and reliability of data transfer is important - that is, in almost all areas of life: when concluding smart contracts for the supply of goods, buying and registering real estate, logistics. This technology enhances the trust, security, transparency, and traceability of data exchanged across a business network.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_kill.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_kill.webp" alt="What business will kill blockchain" />
<figcaption>What kind of business will kill blockchain.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h4 id="banking-and-payments">Banking and payments</h4>

<p>One of the most famous use cases of blockchain is financial transactions. First of all, cryptocurrencies illustrate how this technology can be used in the financial world.</p>

<section class="imp">
  <p><span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <span class="yel bold">How is blockchain better than traditional banks?</span><br />
It uses encryption. This is done using the <a href="/en/articles/mining/#calculating-hashes">hash function</a> and protects data from hacking and manipulation.</span></p>
</section>

<p>In the process of using the blockchain, individual transactions are verified and distributed among the so-called nodes (miners, validators, network participants). This results in a high level of data consistency and a particularly high degree of transparency. These properties are the basis for banking operations.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_transaction.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_transaction.webp" alt="Transactions" />
<figcaption>Transactions on the blockchain.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>This principle opens up interesting applications for international payments. Since verification takes place internally, intermediaries can be eliminated and transaction costs can be reduced. The absence of intermediaries also ensures faster transaction speeds.</p>

<h4 id="healthcare">Healthcare</h4>

<p>The healthcare sector is also showing that blockchain can definitely offer benefits. It can be configured so that only selected users have access to stored data (assets).</p>

<p>In particular, personal documents such as patient records, medical reports, and disease progression can be stored on the blockchain. Access to this data is provided only to selected users who were previously recognized as the owner of the data.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_healthcare.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_healthcare.webp" alt="Blockchain healthcare use case." />
<figcaption>Blockchain healthcare use case.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h4 id="identity-and-personal-data-management">Identity and personal data management</h4>

<p>Identification is a complex task in some business areas. However, with the help of blockchain technology, people’s identities can be identified more safely and quickly than before.</p>

<p>This is based on extensive databases that allow identification and verification. In particular, existing identity documents — driver’s licenses, passports, and ID cards — can be securely implemented digitally. Manipulation would also be virtually impossible.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_identity.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_identity.webp" alt="Identity management" />
<figcaption>Identity management</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Data leakage will also be prevented as the data is stored in a decentralized manner.</p>

<h4 id="insurance">Insurance</h4>

<p>Modern blockchains offer the possibility of developing smart contracts. These are intelligent computer scripts that automatically initiate transactions on the blockchain.</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_smart_contracts.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_smart_contracts.webp" alt="Smart contracts on the blockchain." />
<figcaption>Smart contracts on the blockchain.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The results are predetermined in the contract and depend on the actions of the parties involved in the smart contract. When both parties fulfill their obligations, the smart contract will know what action to take next. <sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>For insurance companies, smart contracts offer great added value because, above all, the processing of claims for damages or insurance payments can be displayed automatically and securely.</p>

<h4 id="supply-chain">Supply chain</h4>

<p>Logistics advantages can be obtained by creating simpler contracts and constantly tracking the relevant goods.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_supplay.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_supplay.webp" alt="Supply chains on the blockchain." />
<figcaption>blockchain in supply chain example.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Thus, the food supply chain will be completely transparently documented from the point of origin to the final supermarket. This is where the advantage of distributed data processing offered by blockchain becomes apparent.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Blockchain in Supply Chain Management? Applications, Advantages, Examples and Trends</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT4M34S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2020-06-15T11:02:01Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/jMihd-gqb6I/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="57609" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/jMihd-gqb6I" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="jMihd-gqb6I"></div>
<span itemprop="description">The use of blockchain in supply chain management is still in its early stages, but there is great potential for this technology to streamline supply chain processes and improve transparency and traceability. </span>
</div>

<blockquote>
  <p>For example, blockchain could be used to track the movement of goods throughout the supply chain, from the point of origin to the point of sale. This would allow all stakeholders to see where the goods are at any given time and make sure that they are being handled properly. Additionally, blockchain could be used to verify the authenticity of goods, ensuring that only certified, safe products are being sold.<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<h4 id="manufacturing">Manufacturing</h4>

<p>The option of distribution of access rights also plays a key role in manufacturing. In addition, the technology can document the ownership of an item and is suitable for use in this area.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_manufacturing.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_manufacturing.webp" alt="How is blockchain changing manufacturing?" />
<figcaption>How is blockchain changing manufacturing?</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>With distributed ledger technology, it will be possible to use the vehicle/equipment when needed and pay directly for the service used.</p>

<h4 id="energy">Energy</h4>

<p>The energy market is also undergoing constant changes. Blockchain technology is preparing to increase the transparency of this market by making transactions traceable.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_electricity.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_electricity.webp" alt="What is the future of blockchain in energy industry." />
<figcaption>What is the future of blockchain in energy industry?</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--ya">For example, the billing of private solar systems can be optimized in this way. Such positive regulation could accelerate the announced energy transition.</p>

<p>Within the framework of electromobility, billing for electronic charging stations can also be implemented in this way and the actual payment process can be ensured.</p>

<h4 id="voting-system">Voting system</h4>

<p>Blockchain technology can also be used in online elections. The base system will be considered a neutral space. Voters could take part in elections without fear of manipulation.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_vote.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_vote.webp" alt="Blockchain voting" />
<figcaption>Blockchain voting system.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>In this way, each voter can also keep track of their vote and check if it was counted correctly. Faking or changing the voice is also not possible.</p>

<h4 id="certification">Certification</h4>

<p>Educational qualifications such as references or certificates are the backbone of professional life and some people rely on fakes to get certified by a well-known specialized institution.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">Using the blockchain, institutions, universities and technical colleges are able to issue diplomas and certificates that cannot be counterfeited. They will be protected by a private key and recognized internationally.</p>

<p>Thus, official certification and sending of original documents will be excluded.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Blockchain Expert Explains One Concept in 5 Levels of Difficulty</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT17M50S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2017-11-28T17:00:30Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/hYip_Vuv8J0/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="5365202" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/hYip_Vuv8J0" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="hYip_Vuv8J0"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Blockchain, the key technology behind Bitcoin, is a new network that helps decentralize trade, and allows for more peer-to-peer transactions.</span>
</div>

<p>WIRED challenged political scientist and blockchain researcher Bettina Warburg to explain blockchain technology to 5 different people; a child, a teen, a college student, a grad student, and an expert.<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></p>

<h2 id="advantages">Advantages</h2>

<p>Top 10 Benefits of Blockchain Technology:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Transparency.</li>
  <li>Reducing transaction costs.</li>
  <li>Flexibility.</li>
  <li>Faster transaction settlement, decentralization, user-controlled network.</li>
  <li>Distributed architecture.</li>
  <li>Openness.</li>
  <li>Automated operations.</li>
  <li>Efficiency, auditability, traceability.</li>
  <li>Safety.</li>
  <li>Worldwide implementation.</li>
</ol>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_benefits.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_benefits.webp" alt="Blockchain Benefits" />
<figcaption>The Benefits of Blockchain</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Thus, the blockchain can guarantee the accuracy and security of data records and create the need for third-party services.<sup id="fnref:6" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote" rel="footnote">6</a></sup></p>

<h2 id="disadvantages">Disadvantages</h2>

<p>Top 10 disadvantages of blockchain technology:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Low performance.</li>
  <li>The problem of scalability.</li>
  <li>Some blockchain solutions consume too much energy.</li>
  <li>It is difficult to correct an error or make adjustments - the data is unchanged.</li>
  <li>Not completely safe.</li>
  <li>High cost and implementation difficulties.</li>
  <li>Expert knowledge required.</li>
  <li>Users must keep private keys.</li>
  <li>Young technology, little implementation experience.</li>
  <li>Low compatibility with old databases.</li>
</ol>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_disadvantages.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/blockchain/en/blockchain_disadvantages.webp" alt="Disadvantages of blockchain" />
<figcaption>Disadvantages of blockchain.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h2>

<p>Blockchain technology still has potential. However, the required computing power, high power consumption are the subject of criticism. PTherefore, numerous developers are working on improvements.</p>

<p class="notice--success">So far, the decentralized database has impressed with its transparency, speed, and security.</p>

<p>The technology can be used in all areas of business. Above all, transparency, decentralization and security play an important role. Many companies are already discovering the possibilities of the technology and developing their own products based on the blockchain. Many experts see great future potential in this technology, so developments in the coming years are likely to be particularly interesting.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Blockchain technology embraced as tool for social good</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT6M53S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-04-08T19:24:30Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/YG9UV5e_CrM/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="5928" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/YG9UV5e_CrM" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="YG9UV5e_CrM"></div>
<span itemprop="description">From bitcoin to NFTs, it feels like blockchain technology is everywhere. But beyond making the already rich that much richer, can it also make society more fair?</span>
</div>

<h3 id="question-answer">Question answer</h3>

<div class="schema-faq-code" itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/FAQPage">
     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">Who checks the network?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Validators, like miners in a Proof-of-Work (PoW) network, are network nodes that operate on Proof-of-Stake (PoS) blockchains, and also verify blocks of transactions in the blockchain.</p>
         </div>
     </div>

     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">Where is transaction data stored?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Blockchain data is stored in a decentralized public ledger. Ledger data is stored in chunks called blocks, which are linked to each other using cryptography.</p>
         </div>
     </div>
</div>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/don_tapscott_how_the_blockchain_is_changing_money_and_business">How the blockchain is changing money and business</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.inc.com/chris-j-snook/4-small-business-verticals-artificial-intelligence-blockchain-will-destroy-in-coming-decade.html">Blockchain and Artificial Intelligence Are Coming to Kill These 4 Small Business Verticals</a> <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://medium.com/pactum/what-is-a-smart-contract-10312f4aa7de">What is a Smart Contract?</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://aims.education/blockchain-supply-chain-management/">Free Lecture on Blockchain in Supply Chain Management, and for more lectures</a> <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/guide-blockchain/">Check out WIRED’s guide to blockchain</a> <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:6" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2022/10/20/advantages-and-disadvantages-of-blockchain-technology/">Advantages And Disadvantages Of Blockchain Technology</a> <a href="#fnref:6" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blockchain: what is it, how does it work and why is it needed? A Simple Guide for the Newest of Beginners.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Decoding the Decade Ahead: A Peek into the Potential Future of Bitcoin</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/blog/btc-potencial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Decoding the Decade Ahead: A Peek into the Potential Future of Bitcoin" /><published>2023-02-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/blog/btc-potencial</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/blog/btc-potencial/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper btc">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      The future of Bitcoin
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>In this article, you will learn about the prospects of bitcoin.</em></p>

<p>The future of <a href="/en/articles/bitcoin">Bitcoin, the world’s first and largest cryptocurrency</a>, is a topic of much speculation and debate. In the decade since its inception, Bitcoin has gone from being a niche asset to a household name, but what does the next 10 years hold for this innovative technology?</p>

<p class="notice--warning">We’ll take a look at some of the key factors that are likely to influence the future of <a href="/en/articles/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> and provide some insights into what we might expect to see in the coming years.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/pic/btc_1.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/pic/btc_1.webp" alt="btc img" /></a></figure>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Founder</th>
      <th>Satoshi Nakamoto</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>💰 Coin</td>
      <td>BTC</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>🎬 Start</td>
      <td>03/03/2009</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>🛍️ Max. quantity</td>
      <td>21,000,000 bitcoins</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>🔮 emission</td>
      <td>18.925.00 BTC</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>🥇 current rank</td>
      <td>#1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>📝 White paper</td>
      <td><a href="https://www.ussc.gov/sites/default/files/pdf/training/annual-national-training-seminar/2018/emerging_Tech_Bitcoin_crypto.pdf">BTC Whitepaper</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="scalability">Scalability</h2>

<p>One of the key challenges facing Bitcoin is scalability<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, the ability of the network to handle increasing numbers of transactions as more people adopt the technology.</p>

<p>Over the next 10 years, it’s likely that the Bitcoin network will need to continue to evolve and adapt to handle the growing demand.</p>

<p class="notice--success">One potential solution is the implementation of the Lightning Network, a second layer payment protocol that enables fast and inexpensive transactions without overwhelming the main Bitcoin network.</p>

<p>If this and other scalability solutions are successfully implemented, it could go a long way in paving the way for wider adoption and growth of Bitcoin.</p>

<h2 id="regulation">Regulation</h2>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Another factor that could significantly impact the future of Bitcoin is regulation<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">In recent years, regulators around the world have begun to take a closer look at cryptocurrencies and many countries have introduced new laws and regulations to govern their use.</p>

<p>While some argue that too much regulation could stifle innovation and limit the potential of cryptocurrencies, others believe that sensible regulation will help to protect consumers and prevent criminal activity.</p>

<p>The next 10 years are likely to see continued debate over the best way to regulate cryptocurrencies, and the outcome of this debate will have a significant impact on the future of Bitcoin.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/pic/btc_2.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/pic/btc_2.webp" alt="btc img" /></a></figure>

<h2 id="institutional-adoption">Institutional Adoption</h2>

<p>In recent years, we’ve already seen a significant increase in institutional interest in cryptocurrencies, particularly Bitcoin. From investment banks and hedge funds to pension funds and endowments, more and more traditional financial players are starting to allocate resources to cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p class="notice--info">This trend is likely to continue in the next 10 years, as institutional investors become more comfortable with the asset class and seek to diversify their portfolios.<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>The entry of institutional investors into the market could help to bring greater stability and credibility to the cryptocurrency market and increase demand for Bitcoin.</p>

<h2 id="technological-developments">Technological Developments</h2>

<p>The world of technology is constantly evolving, and cryptocurrencies are no exception. Over the next 10 years, we can expect to see continued innovation and development in the cryptocurrency space, including the emergence of new technologies and use cases.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">For example, the growth of decentralized finance (DeFi) and non-fungible tokens (NFTs) is already having a major impact on the cryptocurrency market and this trend is likely to continue.</p>

<p>As technology continues to advance, it could open up new opportunities for Bitcoin and help to drive its growth and adoption.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/pic/btc_3.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/pic/btc_3.webp" alt="btc img" /></a></figure>

<h2 id="competition">Competition</h2>

<p>Although Bitcoin is currently the largest and most well-known cryptocurrency, it’s far from the only one.</p>

<p class="notice--primary">Over the next 10 years, we can expect to see continued competition from other cryptocurrencies, including new entrants and established players.<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup></p>

<p>Some of these competitors may offer faster, cheaper or more secure alternatives to Bitcoin, and could potentially challenge its dominance. However, Bitcoin has a significant head start and a strong network effect, which could give it a competitive advantage in the years to come.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>The future of Bitcoin is uncertain, but there are several key factors that will influence its trajectory in the coming years, including scalability, regulation, institutional adoption, and technological developments.</p>

<p>The next 10 years are likely to be a period of growth and evolution for Bitcoin and the broader cryptocurrency market.</p>

<p>While it’s impossible to predict exactly what the future holds, Bitcoin has already come a long way since its creation in 2009 and has the potential to continue playing a significant role in the financial world.</p>

<p class="notice--success">It’s important to do your research and understand the risks and potential rewards before investing in Bitcoin. You should also read through <a href="https://coinwire.com/price-predictions/">articles on price prediction</a> to equip yourself with the necessary knowledge.</p>

<p>With a calculated risk, Bitcoin can offer growth potential and a unique opportunity to participate in the emerging world of cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p>The world of cryptocurrencies is rapidly evolving, making it worth keeping an eye on for those who are seasoned or just starting out in investing. The right approach could lead to growth and wealth creation in the future.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitcoin_scalability_problem">Bitcoin scalability problem</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.thebalancemoney.com/can-bitcoin-regulation-make-cryptocurrency-safer-4173836">Can Bitcoin Regulations Make Cryptocurrency Safer?</a> <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/consensus-magazine/2022/12/28/the-next-wave-of-institutional-digital-asset-adoption/">The Next Wave of Institutional Digital Asset Adoption</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.econstor.eu/bitstream/10419/103022/1/791932281.pdf">Competition in the cryptocurrency market - EconStor</a> <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The future of Bitcoin In this article, you will learn about the prospects of bitcoin.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">What is Crypto Mining? How Does It Work [explained simply]</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/mining/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Crypto Mining? How Does It Work [explained simply]" /><published>2023-02-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/mining</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/mining/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper btc">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      What do mining farms calculate?
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>In this article, you will learn what cryptocurrency mining means.</em></p>

<h2 id="what-is-mining">What is mining?</h2>

<p>New <a href="/en/articles/bitcoin">bitcoins</a> are generated in a process called mining. This process is complicated, but in simple terms, mining is when computers solve mathematical equations, and as a reward they receive bitcoin or other cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p>The term “mining” means “digging”, i.e. creation of new coins. This is done by the so-called miners, who, in the case of bitcoins, add the next block to the blockchain and collect a reward for this. <a href="/en/articles/blockchain/">Blockchain is a ledger</a> that keeps track of how many bitcoins someone has and who transfers them to where.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/what_is_mining_simple.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/what_is_mining_simple.webp" alt="Mining in simple words" />
<figcaption>What is mining in simple words.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="important-terms-and-clear-explanations">Important terms and clear explanations</h2>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<dl>
  <dt>Mining</dt>
  <dd>The process of mining cryptocurrency using the power of computers. Calculations are carried out using specialized integrated circuits (ASIC)<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> or video cards (GPU). These devices solve complex problems (hashes). At the same time, a new block of bitcoins is found, for which miners receive a reward.</dd>
  <dt>Mining farms (mining rig)</dt>
  <dd>Powerful high-performance computing rigs for mining, occupying a significant amount of space. Several devices are combined into farms to make them easier to maintain.</dd>
  <dt>Miner</dt>
  <dd>A person who mines cryptocurrency. The <a href="/en/miners">cryptocurrency mining software</a> itself is also sometimes called a miner.</dd>
</dl>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_definiton.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_definiton.webp" alt="Mining process" />
<figcaption>Mining definition.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--warning">The idea for the name of the process of creating new cryptocoins arose from a comparison with gold miners looking for gold in mines.</p>

<p>In English, the term “mining” refers more to the extraction and extraction of valuable metals in mines and tunnels.</p>

<p>Comparing cryptocurrency mining with gold mining, the name becomes clear. In both forms of mining, miners perform work and are rewarded in the form of an uncirculated asset. Along with digital gold, natural gold is also mined from the ground and becomes part of the economy.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_gold.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_gold.webp" alt="mining" />
<figcaption>Comparing cryptocurrency mining to gold mining.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="how-does-it-work">How does it work</h2>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<p>When using cryptocurrency, transaction details are recorded in the so-called blockchain (registry). The miner is tasked with solving the complex problem behind this transaction. The process ends when the miner confirms the legitimacy of the transaction. Once this is done, the transaction will be visible to everyone on the blockchain.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/what_is_mining.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/what_is_mining.webp" alt="How mining works" />
<figcaption>How mining works.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Simply put, it is about solving complex mathematical problems. Therefore, the transaction verification process requires miners to use high processing power.</p>

<p>The more miners involved in the verification process, the faster the transaction is confirmed. For conducting such a transaction, the miners receive a part of the transaction as a commission. Each successful transaction generates additional new coins that are put into circulation on the blockchain network.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/bitcoin_mining_process.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/bitcoin_mining_process.webp" alt="Mining process and transactions" />
<figcaption>The mining process and transactions.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="what-is-calculated">What is calculated?</h2>

<p>Mining farms are engaged in the calculation of “hashes” according to a given algorithm for cryptocurrency. These hashes are mathematically calculated sequences of letters and numbers stored in blocks.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">The most famous cryptographic hash functions used in cryptocurrency algorithms include “SHA-256” in Bitcoin, “Ethash” in Ethereum Classic, “Scrypt” in Litecoin.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/how_mining.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/how_mining.webp" alt="Mining process" />
<figcaption>Mining process.</figcaption></a></figure>

<h3 id="calculating-hashes">Calculating hashes</h3>

<p>A Bitcoin block contains hashes, which store the hashes of previous blocks, as well as transaction details.</p>

<dl>
  <dt>hash</dt>
  <dd>A hash in the Bitcoin blockchain is a fixed length of a unique sequence of random numbers containing data of any size. Each hash is unique, so you can’t look at a hash and guess what data it contains.</dd>
</dl>

<p>To understand the complex nature of a hash, consider an analogy: every Bitcoin hash is like asking someone to flip a coin 160 times and write it either heads or tails. In the case of heads or tails, there are only two variables on the coin. However, with numbers and letters, the possibilities of a 160-character Bitcoin hash are endless. There will never be two identical values.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_hash.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_hash.webp" alt="What is a hash" />
<figcaption>What is a hash.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>In a hash puzzle, the resulting fingerprint is a list of characters (let’s call it a word), for example, “cat”, after which your task is to find the desired “fingerprint” of this word. To do this, all you can do is try all possible combinations of numbers (of a certain length), one by one.</p>

<h3 id="hashrate-and-hashing">Hashrate and hashing</h3>

<p>To summarize the information above, a hash is a randomly generated alphanumeric code, and hashing is the process of guessing that code. Hashrate here is the speed of mining, hashing (solving the puzzle).</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/hashing.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/hashing.webp" alt="Hashing" />
<figcaption>Hashing is a method of generating a fixed size output from a variable size input.</figcaption></a></figure>

<dl>
  <dt>Hashing</dt>
  <dd>transformation and generation of input data of any length into a fixed-size string, which is performed according to a certain algorithm. Specifically, the Bitcoin hashing algorithm is SHA-256 or 256-bit Secure Hashing Algorithm.</dd>
  <dt>Hashrate</dt>
  <dd>A measure of the processing power per second used in mining. Simply put, this is the speed of mining. It is measured in hash units per second, which means how many calculations can be performed per second. Machines with high hashing power are very efficient and can process a large amount of data per second.</dd>
</dl>

<p class="notice--warning">Here it becomes obvious that the more powerful our hashing machine (aka mining farm), the faster we will find a solution to the algorithm and get income.</p>

<p>But powerful devices will immediately find all Bitcoins, right? No, there is a complexity parameter in the algorithm for this.</p>

<h3 id="network-complexity">Network complexity</h3>

<p>Mining difficulty is how difficult it is to find a given hash below the <span class="yel">target value</span>.</p>

<p>The target value is recalculated every 2016 blocks, with the mining difficulty being inversely proportional to the <span class="yel">target value</span>.</p>

<p>As mining difficulty increases, the <span class="yel">target value</span> decreases, and vice versa.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">In simple terms, for beginners, it is about solving complex mathematical problems. Therefore, the transaction verification process requires miners to use high processing power.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/difficulty.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/difficulty.webp" alt="Network complexity" />
<figcaption>Network complexity</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>As mining speed increases, mining difficulty also increases. As a result, the speed of block creation is reduced to the desired 10 minutes, as mentioned earlier. All this is described in the Proof of Work<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> algorithm.</p>

<p>Once the mining difficulty increases, the average mining time returns to normal and the cycle repeats approximately every 2 weeks.</p>

<h2 id="equipment-and-requirements">Equipment and Requirements</h2>

<p>Mining uses the processing power of a video card (for some cryptocurrencies, a processor) to mine coins such as Monero or Ethereum Classic.</p>

<p>There are also ASICs specially designed devices, such as Bitmain and Antminer.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/asic.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/asic.webp" alt="asics for mining." />
<figcaption>An ASIC chip is 1000 times more efficient at mining than a chip in a home PC.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Cryptocurrency mining requires a special GPU (Graphic Processor Unit) designed to solve complex equations inlittle time. If you want to start crypto mining without your own hardware, so-called cloud mining farms are available.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-better-asic-or-mining-farm">What is better ASIC or mining farm</h3>

<p>Initially, the creators of Bitcoin planned to mine it on the central processing units (CPUs) of widely used laptops or desktop computers. However, ASICs have outperformed both processors and graphics cards (GPUs) due to their lower power consumption and higher processing power.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">Thus, ASICs are better than processors and video cards in mining. They are more powerful in terms of processing power. They can process much more data per unit of time.</p>

<p>Ultimately, more and more miners with high computing power will be more successful than smaller home miners.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/fpga_vs_gpu.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/fpga_vs_gpu.webp" alt="Device Performance Table" />
<figcaption>Device performance table.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The performance hierarchy is as follows:</p>

<ul>
  <li>CPU - The central processing unit of the computer. The lowest efficiency.</li>
  <li>GPU - Graphics processor (video card). Average efficiency.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Field-programmable_gate_array">FPGA - Integrated Circuit</a>. High performance.</li>
  <li>ASIC - Application Specific Integrated Circuit. Top performance.</li>
</ul>

<dl>
  <dt>Pools</dt>
  <dd>Mining rigs allow miners to harness the combined processing power of multiple machines, channel it into mining pools, and distribute a reward (share) for each successfully mined block.</dd>
</dl>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">What is Bitcoin Mining? How Does It Work?</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT16M1S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2018-07-12T13:01:07Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/BODyqM-V71E/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="3516032" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/BODyqM-V71E" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="BODyqM-V71E"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Mining is done by running extremely powerful computers (known as ASICs) that race against other miners in an attempt to guess a specific number.   The first miner to guess the number gets to update the ledger of transactions and also receives a reward of newly minted Bitcoins (currently the reward is 6.25 Bitcoins). </span>
</div>

<h3 id="mining-methods">Mining methods</h3>

<p>There are different approaches to cryptocurrency mining. Here are the 4 most popular types, ranked by the degree of simplicity.</p>

<section class="imp">
  <p><span class="par"><i class="fas fa-mug-hot"></i> <span class="bold">Mining methods:</span> <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">Cloud mining</b>. As the cost of acquiring GPU or ASIC miners is getting higher compared to revenues, cloud mining farms are becoming more and more popular. Cloud mining allows individual miners to take advantage of large corporations and specialized facilities. With a cloud solution, you can rent cloud hardware for a specific period of time. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">CPU mining</b>. In the early days of technology, CPU mining was the easiest way to start mining. To start cryptomining, a simple home PC with a good processor was enough. However, mining on processors is too slow and does not bring that much profit, if you take into account the costs of electricity and cooling. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">GPU mining</b>. Several GPUs, so-called video cards, are combined into a large mining farm, which increases the processing power used. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">ASIC mining</b>. Unlike GPU miners, ASIC miners are specifically designed for cryptocurrency mining, so they can produce more units of cryptocurrency than GPUs. However, the acquisition costs of such ASIC miners are many times higher than those of GPU or CPU miners. <br /></span></p>
</section>

<p>ASIC farms are used for bitcoin mining.</p>

<p>What cryptocurrency is being mined?
All coins with the <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/en/view/pow/">proof of work algorithm</a> can be mined on farms. And mining rig<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> is part of the farm.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_rig_2936.jpg" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/mining_rig_2936.jpg" alt="12 GPU red mining rig." />
<figcaption>12 GPU mining rig</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="mining-is-not-profitable">Mining is not profitable?</h2>

<p>It is said from time to time that mining is dead. There are several factors at work here. Even if the miners are profitable, you must consider upfront costs such as hardware purchases and ongoing electricity costs. Only when all the costs are calculated can one see if it is profitable.</p>

<p>The benefit also depends on the type of equipment. For example, according to a report by the Congressional Research Service, a hash rate of 14 terahashes per second can be obtained either from a single ASIC miner with a power of only 1800 watts, or from more than half a million 40 megawatt Sony game consoles.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Best ASIC Miners For Mining Cryptocurrency In 2023</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT13M29S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-09-23T20:02:45Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/HQnNqneME-c/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="8580" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/HQnNqneME-c" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="HQnNqneME-c"></div>
<span itemprop="description">ASIC miners are specialized computers that only mine crypto, they are oftentimes as powerful as 100 or more GPUs?!</span>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h3 id="halvings-and-rewards">Halvings and rewards</h3>

<p>Bitcoin rewards are halved every four years. This is a process known as halving<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>. Therefore, miners must become more efficient and faster in order to maintain a constant profit.</p>

<ul>
  <li>When Bitcoin was first released in 2009, a miner was earning 50 BTC per block.</li>
  <li>By 2012, the reward was 25 BTC per block.</li>
  <li>After Bitcoin halved in 2016, the reward was halved again to 12.5 coins.</li>
  <li>The reward is currently 6.25 BTC per block.</li>
  <li>The next halving is expected at the end of May 2024. Then the block reward for miners will be halved to 3.125 BTC.</li>
</ul>

<p class="notice--info">In the protocols of many cryptocoins, a halving formula has been introduced. This is important to take into account when calculating.</p>

<h2 id="power-consumption">Power consumption</h2>

<p>You can use various <a href="https://whattomine.com/">online profitability calculators</a> to decide if mining is profitable for you based on electricity cost, device efficiency, mining time and currency value.</p>

<p>According to the Cambridge Center for Alternative Finance, the energy demand of the global Bitcoin network is about 90 terawatt-hours. This currently corresponds to about 0.4 percent of the world’s electricity.</p>

<p>By comparison, air conditioning systems in the US alone last consumed about 2,199 terawatt-hours. This is more than 24 times the energy requirement for global bitcoin mining.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/energy.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/mining/en/energy.webp" alt="Bitcoin electricity consumption." />
<figcaption>Bitcoin electricity consumption</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The BBC estimated Bitcoin’s electricity consumption to be higher than in Argentina (121 TWh), the Netherlands (108.8 TWh) and the United Arab Emirates (113.20 TWh) and is gradually approaching Norway (122.20 TWh). ).<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></p>

<p class="notice--success">Proponents, on the other hand, see more benefit in mining: they argue that mining can protect the power grid from fluctuations or failures. To maintain the power grid, a certain voltage must always be maintained.</p>

<p>Yes, the energy demand for bitcoin mining is high and will continue to rise as the number of miners increases. But network security will also grow.</p>

<p>According to the Bitcoin Mining Council<sup id="fnref:6" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote" rel="footnote">6</a></sup>, almost 60 percent of the energy needed for global Bitcoin mining already comes from natural sources such as wind or solar energy: this share currently stands at 58.9 percent.</p>

<h3 id="what-happens-when-mining-ends">What happens when mining ends?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>The maximum supply of Bitcoin is rigidly defined and will never exceed the limit of almost 21 million coins<sup id="fnref:7" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote" rel="footnote">7</a></sup>. Thus, the supply of BTC cannot be expanded.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Because of the halving, the last bitcoin won’t be mined until around 2140. According to the analytical company Coinmarketcap<sup id="fnref:8" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote" rel="footnote">8</a></sup>, there are currently just over 19 million coins in circulation. This means that it will take miners at least 117 years to mine the remaining two million coins - that is, for the remaining ten percent.</p>

<h2 id="law">Law</h2>

<p>Crypto mining itself is completely legal, but some crypto miners use malware to obtain cryptocurrencies in an illegal way.</p>

<p>This scam is called cryptojacking. These are programs used to covertly search for digital currency on hacked computers.</p>

<h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h2>

<p>Cryptocurrencies are decentralized, that is, neither a central bank, nor a central database, nor a single central authority manages the monetary network. Cryptocurrencies do not have a central authority. Rather, they are run by the cryptocurrency community and, in particular, by cryptocurrency miners.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">GPU mining is dead?</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT13M50S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-11-13T14:00:11Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/RjJcFpJ6snE/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="29954" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/RjJcFpJ6snE" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="RjJcFpJ6snE"></div>
<span itemprop="description">The yield isn't there to compensate for the price declination. Its pretty much a nail in the coffin for home miners.</span>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Miners add transactions to the blockchain. Different cryptocurrencies use different generation methods, if cryptocurrencies use mining at all. (Most cryptocurrencies do not use mining.)</p>

<p>Various mining and consensus methods are used to determine who creates new blocks of transactions and exactly how blocks are added to the blockchain.</p>

<h3 id="question-answer">Question answer</h3>

<div class="schema-faq-code" itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/FAQPage">
     <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">Which cryptocurrency should I mine? </span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">
A promising historical coin rate and low mining difficulty are the most important criteria if you want to mine cryptocurrency.</p>
         </div>
     </div>
	 <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
<span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">Who Invented Mining?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Bitcoin creator Satoshi Nakamoto was the first miner. Information is circulating on the Internet that before the start, he managed to secretly get a big fortune. However, these are just rumors. According to official information, Satoshi was only able to mine 750 coins. The pioneers mined "crypto" using the computer's central processing unit.</p>
         </div>
     </div>
	 <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
<span itemprop="name" class="faq-q">What are the best mining programs?</span>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Best mining software: <a href="/en/miners/phoenixminer/">PhoenixMiner</a>, <a href="/en/miners/nicehash/">NiceHash</a>, <a href="/en/miners/xmrig/">XMRig</a>, <a href="/en/miners/gminer/">Gminer</a>, <a href="/en/miners/lolminer/">Lolminer</a>, <a href="/en/miners/teamredminer/">TeamRedMiner</a> and <a href="/en/miners/trexminer/">T-rex Miner</a>.</p>
         </div>
     </div>
</div>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://bytwork.com/en/komplektujushhie_dlja_majninga/asic">ASIC: TOP list, Comparicon</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof_of_work">Proof of Work (POW, PoW)</a> <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/how-to-build-a-cryptocurrency-mining-rig">What is a mining rig and how to build it</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/uk/advisor/investing/cryptocurrency/bitcoin-halving/">Bitcoin halving. What is it and why is everyone waiting for it</a> <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-56012952">Bitcoin consumes ‘more electricity than Argentina’</a> <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:6" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://bitcoinminingcouncil.com/">Bitcoin Mining Council</a> <a href="#fnref:6" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:7" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/tech/what-happens-bitcoin-after-21-million-mined/">What happens to bitcoins after 21 million is mined?</a> <a href="#fnref:7" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:8" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/en/currencies/bitcoin/">Data from the analytical company Coinmarketcap</a> <a href="#fnref:8" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What do mining farms calculate? In this article, you will learn what cryptocurrency mining means.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Bitcoin: what is it and how does it work (in simple terms)</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/bitcoin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin: what is it and how does it work (in simple terms)" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/bitcoin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/articles/bitcoin/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper btc">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      What is Bitcoin and why is it needed?
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>In this article, you will learn everything about BTC. Let’s explain how virtual money works?</em></p>

<h2 id="what-is-bitcoin">What is bitcoin?</h2>

<p>Bitcoin is a digital and global monetary system, a cryptocurrency. It allows people to send or receive money over the Internet, even from people they don’t know or trust. This is the first technology of its kind that allows the transfer of a digital asset over the Internet without the intervention of a third party.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">Digital money can be exchanged without being tied to a real person. The mathematical field of cryptography is the backbone of Bitcoin security.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is an electronic currency that exists only in the virtual space of the Internet. Also often used is the abbreviation BTC, which is the monetary unit in the Bitcoin system, for which there is a limited supply of 21 million coins<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/what-is-bitcoin.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/what-is-bitcoin.webp" alt="What is Bitcoin" />
<figcaption>Bitcoin is a type of digital currency known as a cryptocurrency.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Bitcoin is the oldest and leading cryptocurrency in the world. The term bitcoin consists of the English words “bit” (digital unit) and “coin” (coin) and means a digital coin. Unlike traditional currencies, BTC does not depend on states and banks.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/about_btc.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/about_btc.webp" alt="Bitcoin description" />
<figcaption>Just about bitcoin.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--primary">To better understand BTC technology, it is important to understand the basic terms.</p>

<h2 id="important-terms-and-clear-explanations">Important terms and clear explanations</h2>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<dl>
  <dt>bitcoin</dt>
  <dd>Digital money designed for decentralized payments, that is, transactions without intermediaries such as banks.</dd>
  <dt>Blockchain</dt>
  <dd>Digital chain of records (blocks). Records of bitcoin payments are stored in each block <a href="/en/articles/blockchain/">(blockchain)</a>.</dd>
  <dt>Cryptocurrency</dt>
  <dd>Bitcoin is also called a cryptocurrency. The Bitcoin payment system uses cryptographic methods to store the information it contains. Cryptography comes from Greek and means secret writing.</dd>
</dl>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/btc_transaction.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/btc_transaction.webp" alt="Bitcoin Transaction" />
<figcaption>How Bitcoin works.</figcaption></a></figure>

<dl>
  <dt>Miner</dt>
  <dd>A member of the Bitcoin network that validates payments and computes new blocks on its hardware.</dd>
  <dt>Mining</dt>
  <dd>The English <a href="/en/articles/mining/">term “mining” means</a> to dig, mine. When miners confirm payments, they receive new bitcoins as a reward. To add a new block to the blockchain, they need to transfer information from the old blocks to the new one with the appropriate ciphers. This requires computing power and huge amounts of electricity.[21].</dd>
</dl>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/how-mining.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/how-mining.webp" alt="Mining Bitcoin" />
<figcaption>How mining works.</figcaption></a></figure>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<section class="imp">
  <p><span class="par"><i class="fas fa-mug-hot"></i> <span class="bold">Too hard? Simple explanation:</span> <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">Bitcoin</b> is money. It has value. It is also similar to stocks because its value fluctuates based on supply and demand. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">Can I touch a Bitcoin?</b> No, BTC is like the money you have available at banks and credit cards. Money moves from one place to another without even touching human hands. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">Who makes crypto coins?</b> To get BTC, you must first mine it. It’s like in a gold mine, only the miners are programs on the Internet. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">How can I see how many coins I have?</b> Nobody can see what you have , spend or receive, but the system itself (blockchain) keeps track of the balances. It’s like a big ledger. <br /></span>
<span class="par"><i class="fas fa-lightbulb"></i> <b class="yel">How do you store BTC then?</b> In a digital wallet. It’s like an app on your smartphone. Only instead of credit card numbers you have a digital access key. You can evenwrite down these keys and store them in your real wallet. <br /></span></p>

</section>

<p>At first glance, it seems that BTC is different from ordinary money, but in fact there are many similarities. It’s just that bitcoin is more modern and functional than debit cards.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is a digital currency that uses blockchain technology to ensure its security.</p>

<h2 id="blockchain">Blockchain</h2>

<p>Physically, there is no cryptocurrency, there are only special registries that track how many bitcoins someone has and who transfers them to where. These registries are called blockchains.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/blockchain-works.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/blockchain-works.webp" alt="Blockchain technology" />
<figcaption>How the blockchain works.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>All purchases, sales and payments in cryptocurrency are stored in blocks of data linked to each other in a chain. This is the blockchain (see terms above). There is a network of people who use their computers to make sure everything is done right. These are miners.</p>

<p class="notice--warning">For their work, miners receive new bitcoins. Each participant has a copy of the blockchain stored on their computer. Therefore, fakes are almost impossible.</p>

<p>Blockchain is a complex database, like a giant ledger of individual blocks of information. The trick is that information is shared and stored in a chain of interconnected blocks. This ensures its security and prevents unauthorized access.</p>

<p class="notice--info">The information recorded on the blockchain remains there forever. Nobody can change her.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is not the only thing that uses blockchain technology – many other cryptocurrencies use it as well. And various companies use the underlying technology for non-cryptocurrency purposes.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">What is Bitcoin? A simple explanation for beginners</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT3M25S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2014-06-25T16:00:41Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/s4g1XFU8Gto/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="2332013" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/s4g1XFU8Gto" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="s4g1XFU8Gto"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Baffled by bitcoin? Confused by the concept of crypto-currencies? Well, fear no more. In 190 seconds we explain what bitcoin actually is, where the idea came from and the impact it's having around the world. Is bitcoin the future of finance, a potential destroyer of the economy ... or just a silly slice of technical utopianism?</span>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h2 id="history">History</h2>

<p>The inventor of BTC is Satoshi Nakamoto (pseudonym of an unknown software developer or development team). In view of the global economic crisis of 2007, he wanted to provide the world community with an independent transaction system that was cryptographically secure, verifiable and immutable.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">The concept and open source software were published between 2008 and 2009 by an individual or group of individuals under the pseudonym Satoshi Nakamoto. It is still not clear who is behind this.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Mystery Founder Of Bitcoin: Uncovering Satoshi Nakamoto's Identity Of Bitcoin Matters</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT6M35S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2017-10-27T15:59:02Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Bze53qwHS8o/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="1110043" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/Bze53qwHS8o" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="Bze53qwHS8o"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Experts agree that uncovering Satoshi Nakamoto's identity could have an immense impact on bitcoin's economics and internal politics.</span>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>What is certain, however, is that Nakamoto released the first version of the Bitcoin Core reference implementation in 2009, thereby laying the foundation for Bitcoin, which was the first cryptocurrency in history.</p>

<p class="notice--warning">The first goods paid for with Bitcoin were two pizzas in 2010 that cost 10,000 BTC. 10 years later, Bitcoin owners could buy a mega yacht or a private jet for the same amount.</p>

<h3 id="historical-price--events">Historical Price &amp; Events</h3>

<p>In 2009, the exchange rate of one Bitcoin was about one dollar. In November 2021, the value of the cryptocurrency exceeded $69,000, which is a record high.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/history_price_btc.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/history_price_btc.webp" alt="BTC price history 2009-2023" />
<figcaption>BTC price history.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--warning"><i class="fab fa-bitcoin"></i> Price history:
2009 - 1$,
2021 - about $69,000,
May 2022 - only $27,000.September 2022 - below $19,000.</p>

<p>Volatility means both big rewards and big risks for everyone who owns Bitcoin.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">What is The History of Bitcoin: Super Easy Explanation</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT12M11S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2018-01-10T15:00:03Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/khtCG_15bsY/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="75353" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/khtCG_15bsY" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="khtCG_15bsY"></div>
<span itemprop="description">A short documentary on the history of cryptocurrency, including Bitcoin.</span>
</div>

<h3 id="why-is-there-so-much-noise-around-bitcoin">Why is there so much noise around Bitcoin?</h3>

<p>The value of Bitcoin has skyrocketed in recent years. Only in the last five years, the cost has increased by about a hundred times.</p>

<p class="notice--success">Anyone who bought BTC with €100 in 2009 is now a multimillionaire. It awakens desires.</p>

<p>Recently, institutional investors and international corporations are increasingly investing part of their assets in Bitcoin. This led to a further increase in prices. But no one can say if this will continue.</p>

<p>The value of digital assets is subject to sharp fluctuations. Therefore, the savings you urgently need should never be invested in digital assets because the price risk is huge. BTC is not a safe investment.</p>

<h3 id="interesting-facts">Interesting Facts</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Bitcoin was launched in 2009 and hit its all-time high in 2021.</li>
  <li>668 million transactions have already been made.</li>
  <li>The last coin will be mined in 2140.</li>
  <li>About 20% of bitcoins are lost forever. Users have lost their private keys to them.</li>
</ul>

<dl>
  <dt>Private key</dt>
  <dd>is a secure code that allows its owner to conduct cryptocurrency transactions and confirm ownership of their property. Bitcoin keys contain a 256-bit string, displayed as a combination of letters and numbers.</dd>
</dl>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Fun Facts About Bitcoin</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT1M59S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2017-08-11T21:51:23Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/uCdyUOczZCA/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="766" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/uCdyUOczZCA" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="uCdyUOczZCA"></div>
<span itemprop="description">We’re sharing our top five fun facts about Bitcoin.</span>
</div>

<ul>
  <li>Buying a pizza was the first commercial bitcoin transaction.</li>
  <li>There are nearly 100,000 Bitcoin millionaires.</li>
  <li>Bitcoins can be bought and put into digital wallets.</li>
</ul>

<dl>
  <dt>Bitcoin wallet</dt>
  <dd>The software is a <a href="/en/wallets/">digital wallet</a>. This is where bitcoins are stored.</dd>
</dl>

<p class="notice--success">In practice, BTC is in the so-called wallet on a PC or mobile phone. They are protected by a very long password. Storing cryptocurrencies on your own device is called “cold storage”. This is the most secure storage method.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">Online platforms or <a href="https://bytwork.com/en/markets">cryptocurrency exchanges</a> also offer wallets linked to a user account. These are so-called “hot wallets”, which can be accessed using a computer or smartphone. This is the least secure storage method because the exchange can be hacked.</p>

<h2 id="what-does-bitcoin-look-like">What does bitcoin look like?</h2>

<p>Bitcoin has no coins or banknotes. Cryptocurrency exists only virtually, like a string of digital characters in a computer program.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/btc_look.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/en/btc_look.webp" alt="What Bitcoin looks like" />
<figcaption>What Bitcoin looks like.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Virtual currency is fundamentally different from currencies such as the euro or the dollar. Behind the latter are economic powers and central banks that provide security and stability. Bitcoin does not have this, which ensures that it is not tracked or protected.</p>

<h2 id="advantages">Advantages</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Cryptocurrencies are available worldwide and operate independently of states.</li>
  <li>Blockchain technology is considered very secure.</li>
  <li>The basis is a decentralized database, a blockchain stored on several computers and managed jointly by the participants. All transactions are protected from forgery using cryptographic methods.</li>
  <li>Unlike classic money, the new coins are notare issued and not controlled by a central authority such as a central bank, but are created and managed decentralized through cryptographic computing on the network.</li>
  <li>Unlike classical currencies such as dollars or euros, an unlimited amount of BTC cannot be created. There is a limit of 21 million. Most of the coins have already been created.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/btc_1.jpg" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/articles/bitcoin/btc_1.jpg" alt="cryptocurrency" /> </a></p>

<p>In addition, the internet currency is considered to be inflation resistant as its absolute amount is capped at 21 million.
This was also the goal of the inventor Satoshi Nakamoto (pseudonym for an unknown software developer or software development team).</p>

<p>In view of the global economic crisis of 2007, the creator wanted to provide the world community with an independent transaction system that would be cryptographically secure, verifiable and immutable.</p>

<h3 id="safety">Safety</h3>

<p>Payment transactions are carried out and protected using the blockchain. This means that other participants in the Bitcoin network are of central importance. Many other computers on the network participate in the payment transaction, making the encryption very secure from manipulation. For providing computing power, the rest of the participants again receive bitcoins - this is how new bitcoins are created.</p>

<h2 id="criticism">Criticism</h2>

<h3 id="volatility">Volatility</h3>

<p>The price of bitcoin is considered unstable, volatile<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>. This means that it is subject to strong fluctuations.</p>

<p>The price of bitcoin fluctuates much more than stock prices. In November 2021, one bitcoin was worth $69,000, in May 2022 it dropped to $27,000. This is a difference of more than 50 percent.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is a digital currency, there is no real value behind it, as, for example, is the case with gold. In addition, BTC is not a national currency.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">The Dangers of Bitcoin - Analysing Risks Ahead For Bitcoin In 2023</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT16M58S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2018-01-31T16:29:17Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/MSpWAYwqXQ4/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="168723" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/MSpWAYwqXQ4" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="MSpWAYwqXQ4"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Before you buy bitcoin, or tell someone else to do so, make sure you understand these fundamental risks. </span>
</div>

<h3 id="shadow-market">Shadow market</h3>

<p>Critics believe that criminogenic elements use bitcoin to trade drugs or weapons. Hackers blackmail companies by shutting down computer systems and demanding a ransom in bitcoin. You can buy bitcoins anonymously. This is why digital currency has always been so popular among criminals.</p>

<p class="notice--primary">However, following this logic, cash is also used to trade in drugs or weapons. This does not mean that cash should be banned.</p>

<h3 id="high-risks">High risks</h3>

<p>Bitcoin has a reputation for being a non-transparent object of speculation, rather than a convenient, independent, and widespread means of payment. Some people have become very rich because of this - in fiat money like euros and dollars - others have lost a lot of money.</p>

<p>If law abiding citizens want to use Bitcoin, this is not possible anonymously due to government regulations, and a normal bank account is usually required, so Bitcoin is not independent of banks and governments.</p>

<h3 id="other-disadvantages">Other disadvantages</h3>

<ul>
  <li>As a result of hacker attacks on large crypto platforms, amounts of several million euros have disappeared.</li>
  <li>Cryptographic verification of transactions in the blockchain and the creation of new coins require gigantic power consumption.</li>
  <li>It is estimated that the global bitcoin network consumes as much electricity as Sweden in 2022.</li>
  <li>If you lose the private key to your virtual wallet, then digital money will be lost.</li>
  <li>Future hacker attacks cannot be completely ruled out.</li>
  <li>There are no contracts and legal guarantees.</li>
  <li>If the Internet collapsed, then the digital currency could no longer be used.</li>
</ul>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://learn.bybit.com/en/crypto/21-million-bitcoin-limit-mined/">21 million bitcoin limit</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/052014/why-bitcoins-value-so-volatile.asp">What is volatility in Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is Bitcoin and why is it needed? In this article, you will learn everything about BTC. Let’s explain how virtual money works?]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Check Which Route For Specific Domain In Linux</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/specific-domain-linux/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Check Which Route For Specific Domain In Linux" /><published>2022-12-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/specific-domain-linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/specific-domain-linux/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper wallet">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
	How to create custom routes for specific domains in Linux.    
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>We’ll show you how to use the route command to find the best DNS route for your web server.</em></p>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Many Linux users are familiar with the concept of a default route. This is a route that your computer automatically uses when it needs to send traffic to a specific destination. But what about when you need to use a different route for specific domains? In this article, we will show you how to create custom routes for specific domains in Linux.</p>

<p>Some systems prefer certain routes to be used for communications between different parts of the operating system. For example, on a Unix-based system, the default route might be used to send traffic destined for the network interface card (NIC) to the appropriate kernel module.</p>

<p class="notice--warning">Knowing which route is being used can help troubleshoot problems.</p>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="stream-hulu-with-a-vpn-keep-your-privacy-intact">Stream Hulu with a VPN: Keep your privacy intact</h2>

<p>If you’re looking to <a href="https://www.vpnblade.com/vpn-for-hulu/">access Hulu with VPN</a>, keep your privacy intact. Hulu is owned by Disney, and as such, it is subject to a number of restrictions and regulations. These range from requiring viewers to abide by copyright laws to block certain types of advertisements.</p>

<p class="notice--success">In addition, Hulu has been known to engage in data tracking. By using a VPN, you can protect your privacy and keep your browsing activities private.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-choose-the-right-route-for-a-specific-domain-in-linux">How To Choose The Right Route For A Specific Domain In Linux?</h2>

<p>When choosing a route for a specific domain in Linux, it is important to consider the traffic patterns and requirements of your network. There are several different routes that can be chosen depending on the needs of your network. The following are four different routes that can be adopted when routing traffic in Linux:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Static Route</strong>: A static route is defined once and never changes. This is the most common route type used in Linux because it is easy to set up and does not require any configuration on routers or firewalls.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Dynamic Route</strong>: A dynamic route is created each time a packet is routed through the system. This type of route can be more complicated to set up, but it offers greater flexibility because it can update automatically based on changes in the network.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>To display the current routing table in Linux, run the command:</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c"># ip route</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">default via 192.168.1.1 dev enp0s3</code> – default gateway, in this example, working through interface <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">enp0s3</code>. If there is no route for the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">target</code> address in the routing table, then such a packet is sent through this gateway (default route)</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">192.168.1.0/24 dev enp0s3 proto kernel scope link src 192.168.1.201</code> - static route for the network <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">192.168.1.0/24</code> through the address <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">192.168.1.201</code>, which is registered on the interface</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">proto kernel</code> - route created by kernel ( proto static - route added by administrator)</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">metric</code> – route priority (the lower the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">metric</code> value, the higher the priority). If there are two routes with the same metric (don’t do that!), the kernel starts randomly selecting routes.
To find out through which interface (gateway) traffic should be routed to a specific IP address, use the command:</li>
</ul>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c"># ip route get 192.168.2.45</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="how-to-find-the-best-dns-route-for-your-web-server-in-linux">How To Find The Best Dns Route For Your Web Server In Linux?</h2>

<p>In this article, we’ll show you how to use the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">route</code> command to find the best DNS route for your web server.</p>

<p class="notice--success">A routed command is a powerful tool that can be used to manipulate network traffic in Linux.</p>

<p>By using the route command, you can determine which packets should be forwarded through your server based on their destination addresses. This can be helpful if you need to configure your server in a specific way, such as routing all traffic for a specific domain through your web server.</p>

<p>To use the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">route</code> command, you first need to know which domain name you want to route traffic for. You can find this information by querying your DNS provider or by looking at your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/etc/hosts</code> file.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">GNU/Linux - Adding a Static Route using the route Command (i.e. TCP/IP)</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT3M24S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2013-06-30T20:11:35Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/EUSNTbJA5fI/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="34941" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/EUSNTbJA5fI" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="EUSNTbJA5fI"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Route manipulates the kernel's IP routing tables. Its primary use is to set up static routes to specific hosts or networks via an interface after it has been configured with the ifconfig(8) program.  When the add or del options are used, route modifies the routing tables. Without these options, route displays the current contents of the routing tables.</span>
</div>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>route <span class="nt">-n</span>
route add <span class="nt">-net</span> 192.168.7.0 netmask 255.255.255.0 gw 192.168.1.2 dev eth0
</code></pre></div></div>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Linux Route Add Command with examples</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT3M10S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2016-07-22T08:26:42Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/3JtGTIlTsn0/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="26333" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/3JtGTIlTsn0" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="3JtGTIlTsn0"></div>
<div itemprop="description">
<p>This video explains Linux route add command. It is the basic design for internet protocol. This protocol helps in transferring packet to the right machines. </p>
<p class="notice--ya">For more explanation on this video: <a href="https://www.linuxhelp.com/route-command-in-linux-with-examples">https://www.linuxhelp.com/route-command-in-linux-with-examples</a></p></div>
</div>

<p>route syntax:</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>route add <span class="o">[</span><span class="nt">-net</span>|-host] &lt;IP/Net&gt; netmask gw &lt;Gateway IP&gt; dev &lt;Int&gt;X
</code></pre></div></div>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="o">[</span>root@miningsoft ~]# route
Kernel IP routing table
Destination     Gateway         Genmask         Flags Metric Ref    Use Iface
default         192.168.5.1     0.0.0.0         UG    1024   0        0 eno16777736
192.168.5.0     0.0.0.0         255.255.255.0   U     0      0        0 eno16777736
</code></pre></div></div>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="o">[</span>root@miningsoft ~]# route add <span class="nt">-net</span> 192.168.5.0 netmask 255.255.255.0 gw 192.168.5.1 eno16777736
<span class="o">[</span>root@miningsoft ~]# route
Kernel IP routing table
Destination     Gateway         Genmask         Flags Metric Ref    Use Iface
default         192.168.5.1     0.0.0.0         UG    1024   0        0 eno16777736
192.168.5.0     192.168.5.1     255.255.255.0   UG    0      0        0 eno16777736
192.168.5.0     0.0.0.0         255.255.255.0   U     0      0        0 eno16777736
</code></pre></div></div>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="o">[</span>root@miningsoft ~]# route add <span class="nt">-host</span> 192.168.5.191 gw 192.168.5.1 eno16777736
<span class="o">[</span>root@miningsoft ~]# route
Kernel IP routing table
Destination     Gateway         Genmask         Flags Metric Ref    Use Iface
default         192.168.5.1     0.0.0.0         UG    1024   0        0 eno16777736
192.168.5.0     192.168.5.1     255.255.255.0   UG    0      0        0 eno16777736
192.168.5.0     0.0.0.0         255.255.255.0   U     0      0        0 eno16777736
192.168.5.191   192.168.5.1     255.255.255.255 UGH   0      0        0 eno16777736
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="which-linux-route-is-right-for-your-site">Which Linux Route Is Right For Your Site?</h2>
<p>Linux offers a variety of ways to route traffic to specific sites. This can be useful when you need to control how users access certain parts of your site, or when you want to manage traffic load on specific sections of your site.</p>

<p>There are three main ways Linux routes traffic:</p>

<ol>
  <li>via a direct route,</li>
  <li>via an indirect route,</li>
  <li>and through a proxy server.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Direct routing</strong> is the simplest type of routing, and it uses the IP address of the destination site as the source address for outgoing packets.</p>

<p>This approach is best suited for sites that require a consistent level of security and reliability.</p>

<p><strong>Indirect routing</strong> involves sending packets through one or more intermediate hosts before they reach their destination.</p>

<p>This approach can improve performance because it reduces the number of hops required to reach the destination site. However, indirect routing can also introduce vulnerabilities if the intermediate hosts are compromised.</p>

<h2 id="system-administrator-trying-to-optimize-linux-traffic-to-save-bandwidth">System Administrator Trying To Optimize Linux Traffic To Save Bandwidth?</h2>

<p>Linux is a powerful operating system that can be used to optimize traffic on a network. It’s possible to route traffic for specific domains through a Linux server in order to save bandwidth.</p>

<p>This type of optimization can be useful if you have a lot of traffic coming from one domain and want to redirect it through your server.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-check-if-a-website-is-running-on-linux">How To Check If A Website Is Running On Linux?</h2>

<p>Running a website on Linux can be a great option for those who are looking to save money on hosting costs, or who want to run their site without relying on the third-party domain name and hostname of your website.</p>

<p>If you are using a custom domain name, you can use the route command to reach <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Queervices</code>. However, in order to ensure that your website is running on Linux, it is important to check your DNS server for the hostname of your site.</p>

<p>If you are using a hosted domain name, you can contact your hosting provider to find out the hostname of your site. Additionally, you can use a web browser extension like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">WhoIsHostingThis</code> to determine the hostname of your site.</p>

<h2 id="final-words">Final Words</h2>

<p>It is important to know which route for a specific domain will be the most efficient for your needs. There are many options open to you, so it is important to do your research to find the best option for your needs.</p>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to create custom routes for specific domains in Linux. We’ll show you how to use the route command to find the best DNS route for your web server.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">EthPow: How to mine, Pools, Miners, Exchanges, Get a wallet</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/ethw/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EthPow: How to mine, Pools, Miners, Exchanges, Get a wallet" /><published>2022-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/ethw</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/ethw/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper wallet">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      What is EthereumPoW and how to mine it?
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>In this guide, you will learn about ETHW - a fork of Ethereum for mining on video cards and ASICs</em></p>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>ETHPoW is a Proof-of-Work (PoW) blockchain created after the transition of <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking/">Ethereum to staking</a>.</p>

<p><dfn>EthereumPoW</dfn> (abbreviated ETHW) is a token launched as part of the EthereumPoW program, the purpose of which is to preserve the version of <a href="/en/guide/merge/">Merge-mined Ethereum</a>. The release date of the coin is September 15, 2022. You can get a 1:1 airdrop with ETH lying on the same address with ETHW.</p>

<h2 id="system-requirements">System requirements</h2>

<p>The system requirements for mining are the same as for Ethereum:</p>

<ul class="notice--primary">
  <li>Mining equipment: GPU (NVIDIA or AMD, video memory at least 6 GB) or several ASICs.</li>
  <li>Operating system: Windows, Linux.</li>
  <li>Virtual memory: set 6 GB of virtual memory for one video card (for example, set 36 GB for 6 video cards).</li>
  <li>Mining software: <a href="/en/miners/phoenixminer/">PhoenixMiner</a>, <a href="/en/miners/lolminer/">lolMiner</a>, <a href="/en/miners/nbminer/">NBMiner</a>, <a href="/en/miners/gminer/">GMiner</a>, <a href="/en/miners/trexminer/">T-rex Miner</a> etc.</li>
</ul>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<section id="how-to-start" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowTo">
<h2 itemprop="name" id="Как майнить ETHW?">How to mine ETHW?</h2>
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step1" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="#step1" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
		<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="1. Get a wallet address">1. Get a wallet address</h3>
		<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">

<p>You can get a wallet either at <a href="https://metamask.io/">MetaMask</a> or on the exchange. Consider both options.</p>
<p>You need to register on the exchange using <a href="https://cutt.ly/b8fRKBL">registration form</a>. Fill out the form with your email address and a secure password.</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/exchanges/kuna/signup.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/exchanges/kuna/signup.png" alt=" signup" /> <figcaption>Sign up.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>You will also need to accept the terms of service and privacy policy. The account will then be activated by verification via the link you will receive in your email.</p>

<p>Second alternative - <span class="bold">get the wallet address in MetaMask</span>.</p>
<p>To do this, go <a href="https://metamask.io/">to the official MetaMask website</a> and install the extension:</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/download.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/download.png" alt=" Loading" /> <figcaption>Loading.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>This will open <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/metamask/nkbihfbeogaeaoehlefnkodbefgpgknn">Chrome Web Store</a> and prompt you to begin installation:</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/chrome_install.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/chrome_install.png" alt=" Installation" /> <figcaption>Installation.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>You will see a welcome window:</p>
<figure> <a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/welcome.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/welcome.png" alt=" welcome" /><figcaption>Password.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>Next you need to agree to the terms:</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/agree.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/agree.png" alt=" agree" /> <figcaption>Conditions.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>Then MetaMask will ask: do you want to create a new wallet or import an existing one?</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/import_create.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/import_create.png" alt=" import_create" /> <figcaption>import or create.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p><span class="bold">If you want to receive an Airdrop, then use an existing wallet with an Ethereum balance.</span> You can either use a TID phrase or </p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/password.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/password.png" alt=" password" /> <figcaption>Password.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>The wallet will prompt you to create and save a seed phrase:</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/seed.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/seed.png" alt=" seed" /> <figcaption>Seed Phrase.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>It is imperative to write down these words. Example: <code>tank sphere calm license net film husband category lizard recall energy series
</code></p>
<p>The next step will ask you to confirm the phrase and enter these words. You need to follow the sequence:</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/seed2.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/seed2.png" alt=" seed" /> <figcaption>Seed Phrase.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>After confirming the seed phrase, you will be logged in:</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/account.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/account.png" alt=" account" /> <figcaption>Account.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p></p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/ethw.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/wallets/metamask/ethw.png" alt=" ethw" /> <figcaption>Ethw.</figcaption></a></figure> 


		</div>
	</div>
	
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step2" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="#step2" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
		<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="2. Install mining software">2. Install mining software</h3>
		<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">
		<div>
<p>ETHW is added using the <code>ethash</code> algorithm. Install software that supports the mining of coins of this algorithm.</p>
<table>
  <caption>ETHW Miners</caption>
<thead>
<tr>
<td>Miner</td>
<td>Fees</td>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="/en/miners/phoenixminer">PhoenixMiner</a></td>
<td>0.65%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="/en/miners/gminer">GMiner</a></td>
<td>1%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="/en/miners/lolminer">LolMiner</a></td>
<td>0.7%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="/en/miners/nbminer">NBMiner</a></td>
<td>1%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="/en/miners/trexminer">T-Rex Miner</a></td>
<td>1%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="/en/miners/teamredminer">TeamRedMiner</a></td>
<td>1%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="/en/miners/nicehash">NiceHash</a></td>
<td>2%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>To install, just download the archive with the program and extract it. Then you need to open the file <code>start.bat</code> and enter your wallet into it.</p>
	
</div>
</div>
	</div>
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step3" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="/#step3" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.jpg" />
	<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="3. Enter the wallet address">3. Enter the wallet address</h3>
	<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">
<p>Open the file <code>start.bat</code> and enter the wallet address obtained in the first step into it.</p>
<p>Example for PhoenixMiner:</p>
<p><code>PhoenixMiner.exe -pool eu.ethwmine.com:8008 -wal 0x1DE28FDcfF94656CBaCe3557FF1239CC0F61a3cE -worker phoenix -pass x -log 0 -retrydelay 1 -Rmode 1 -fret 1 -rate 1 -coin ETH
pause</code></p>
<p>After saving the configuration, open and run the "start.bat" batch file to start mining.</p>
	</div>
	</div>
<div class="panel panel-default" id="videoguide" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="/#videoguide" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
	<div class="panel-body">
	<meta itemprop="text" content="Как стейкать ETH 2.0 на Binance от 0.1$. Что делать с BETH" />
<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">How to mine the new ETHW coin</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT14M13S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-09-16T17:00:21Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ooxQ30wrLi0/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="22192" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/ooxQ30wrLi0" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="ooxQ30wrLi0"></div>
<span itemprop="description">How to mine the new ETH Fork - EthereumPOW</span>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">How To Mine Ethw (Eth Pow) And Etf - Ipollo V1 Mini Se Asic Miner (Ethw, Etc)</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT14M" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-09-16T14:29:00Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/xKyx3ENenU0/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="23575" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/xKyx3ENenU0" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="xKyx3ENenU0"></div>
<span itemprop="description">how much do you make from ethw? like how many tokens? 0.05 a day.</span>
</div>

<h2 id="mining">Mining</h2>

<p>Setting up mining using the <a href="/en/miners/lolminer/">LolMiner</a>.</p>

<p>EthereumPOW only:</p>

<div class="language-batch highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">lolMiner</span><span class="err">.exe</span> <span class="na">--algo </span><span class="kd">ETHASH</span> <span class="na">--pool </span><span class="kd">pool</span>.woolypooly.com:3096 <span class="na">--user </span><span class="mh">0x0a753EE6989480e6CE633860508269a2CCfaE34A</span>.WORKER_NAME
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>EthereumPOW (ETHW) + Alephium Dual Mining:</p>

<div class="language-batch highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">lolMiner</span><span class="err">.exe</span> <span class="na">--algo </span><span class="kd">ETHASH</span> <span class="na">--pool </span><span class="kd">pool</span>.woolypooly.com:3096 <span class="na">--user </span><span class="mh">0x0a753EE6989480e6CE633860508269a2CCfaE34A</span>.WORKER_NAME <span class="na">--dualmode </span><span class="kd">ALEPHDUAL</span> <span class="na">--dualpool </span><span class="kd">pool</span>.woolypooly.com:3106 <span class="na">--dualuser </span><span class="m">14</span><span class="kd">xchBfD4bwxdti44NyjK5BQWympyHuxAREigL2UkZCgZ</span>.WORKER_NAME
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>EthereumPOW (ETHW) + Kaspa Dual Mining:</p>

<div class="language-batch highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">lolMiner</span><span class="err">.exe</span> <span class="na">--algo </span><span class="kd">ETHASH</span> <span class="na">--pool </span><span class="kd">pool</span>.woolypooly.com:3096 <span class="na">--user </span><span class="mh">0x0a753EE6989480e6CE633860508269a2CCfaE34A</span>.WORKER_NAME <span class="na">--dualmode </span><span class="kd">KASPADUAL</span> <span class="na">--dualpool </span><span class="kd">pool</span>.woolypooly.com:3112 <span class="na">--dualuser </span><span class="kd">kaspa</span><span class="nl">:qrkqwe</span><span class="m">4</span><span class="kd">kzpd8hv3l4fatgzyzj4l3yygrs2yqx4nvz08lsgzdpqc8zt302prna</span>.WORKER_NAME
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="phoenix-miner">Phoenix Miner</h3>

<p>Setting up mining using the <a href="/en/miners/phoenixminer/">PhoenixMiner</a>:</p>

<div class="language-batch highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">PhoenixMiner</span><span class="err">.exe</span> <span class="na">-pool </span><span class="kd">ssl</span>://ethw.pool<span class="na">-moscow</span>.ru:9009 <span class="na">-wal </span><span class="mh">0x1DE28FDcfF94656CBaCe3557FF1239CC0F61a3cE</span> <span class="na">-worker </span><span class="kd">phoenix</span> <span class="na">-pass </span><span class="kd">x</span> <span class="na">-log </span><span class="m">0</span> <span class="na">-retrydelay </span><span class="m">1</span> <span class="na">-Rmode </span><span class="m">1</span> <span class="na">-fret </span><span class="m">1</span> <span class="na">-rate </span><span class="m">1</span> <span class="na">-coin </span><span class="kd">ETH</span>
<span class="nb">pause</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="gminer">Gminer</h3>

<p>Setting up mining using the <a href="/en/miners/gminer/">Gminer</a>:</p>

<p>Ethw+Kaspa on the pool <a href="https://woolypooly.com/en/coin/ethw">woolypooly</a></p>

<div class="language-batch highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">miner</span><span class="err">.exe</span> <span class="na">--algo </span><span class="kd">ethash</span> <span class="na">--server </span><span class="kd">ethw</span>.2miners.com:2020 <span class="na">--user </span><span class="mh">0x0a753EE6989480e6CE633860508269a2CCfaE34A</span> <span class="na">--dalgo </span><span class="kd">kheavyhash</span> <span class="na">--dserver </span><span class="kd">pool</span>.eu.woolypooly.com:3112 <span class="na">--duser </span><span class="kd">kaspa</span><span class="nl">:qrkqwe</span><span class="m">4</span><span class="kd">kzpd8hv3l4fatgzyzj4l3yygrs2yqx4nvz08lsgzdpqc8zt302prna</span>
<span class="nb">pause</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="nbminer">Nbminer</h3>

<p>An example of a .bat file for <a href="/en/miners/nbminer/">NbMiner</a></p>

<div class="language-batch highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">nbminer</span><span class="err">.exe</span> <span class="na">-a </span><span class="kd">ethash</span> <span class="na">-o </span><span class="kd">ethproxy</span><span class="na">+tcp</span>://pool.woolypooly.com:3096 <span class="na">-u </span><span class="mh">0x0a753EE6989480e6CE633860508269a2CCfaE34A</span>.WORKER_NAME
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="t-rex">T-rex</h3>

<p>Example .bat file for <a href="/en/miners/trexminer/">Trexminer</a></p>

<div class="language-batch highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">t</span><span class="na">-rex -a </span><span class="kd">ethash</span> <span class="na">-o </span><span class="kd">stratum</span><span class="na">+tcp</span>://pool.woolypooly.com:3096 <span class="na">-u </span><span class="mh">0x0a753EE6989480e6CE633860508269a2CCfaE34A</span>.WORKER_NAME <span class="na">-p </span><span class="kd">x</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="pools-and-fees">Pools and Fees</h2>

<table role="grid">
	<colgroup>
		<col span="3" />
	</colgroup>
<thead>
		<tr>
			<td>#</td>
			<td>
			Pool
			&nbsp;
			</td>
			<td>
			Fee
			</td>
		</tr>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">2</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw.2miners.com/" target="_blank">2miners.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">3</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://www.jingniupool.com/" target="_blank">jingniupool.com</a></td>
			<td>0&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS+</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">4</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://www.poolin.com/" target="_blank">poolin.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">5</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw.nanopool.org/" target="_blank">nanopool.org</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">6</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ezil.me/" target="_blank">ezil.me&nbsp;+</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">7</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://www.x-pool.io/" target="_blank">x-pool.io</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS+</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">8</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://antpool.com/" target="_blank">antpool.com</a></td>
			<td>1.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS+</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">9</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://richpool.pro/" target="_blank">richpool.pro</a></td>
			<td>0.1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS+</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="4">10</td>
			<td rowspan="4"><a href="https://woolypooly.com/" target="_blank">woolypooly.com&nbsp;+</a></td>
			<td>0.9&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>0.9&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">11</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://k1pool.com/pool/ethw" target="_blank">k1pool.com&nbsp;+</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>RBPPS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">12</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://pool.binance.com/" target="_blank">binance.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>FPPS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">13</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw.solopool.org/" target="_blank">solopool.org[SOLO]</a></td>
			<td>1.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">14</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://solo-ethw.2miners.com/" target="_blank">2miners.com[SOLO]</a></td>
			<td>1.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">15</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://gteh.org/" target="_blank">gteh.org&nbsp;+</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="4">16</td>
			<td rowspan="4"><a href="https://ethw.herominers.com/" target="_blank">herominers.com&nbsp;+</a></td>
			<td>0.9&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PROP</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>0.9&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="4">17</td>
			<td rowspan="4"><a href="https://www.666pool.com/" target="_blank">666pool.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">18</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethwmine.com/" target="_blank">ethwmine.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">19</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://pool.kryptex.com/" target="_blank">kryptex.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS+</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">20</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://www.dogpool.one/" target="_blank">dogpool.one</a></td>
			<td rowspan="2">&nbsp;</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">21</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw.pool-moscow.ru/" target="_blank">pool-moscow.ru</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">22</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://k1pool.com/pool/ethwsolo" target="_blank">k1pool.com&nbsp;+&nbsp;[SOLO]</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">23</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw.crazypool.org/" target="_blank">crazypool.org&nbsp;+</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>D-PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="4">24</td>
			<td rowspan="4"><a href="https://baikalmine.com/" target="_blank">baikalmine.com</a></td>
			<td>0.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>0.75&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS+</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">25</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw-pplns.molepool.com/" target="_blank">molepool.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">26</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://coolpool.top/pool?coin=ethwSolo&amp;type=solo" target="_blank">coolpool.top[SOLO]</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">27</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://zetpool.org/pps-ethw" target="_blank">zetpool.org</a></td>
			<td>0.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">28</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://miningmadness.com/" target="_blank">miningmadness.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PROP</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">29</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw.molepool.com/" target="_blank">molepool.com[SOLO]</a></td>
			<td>1.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">30</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethw.ua-mining.com/" target="_blank">ua-mining.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">31</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://cruxpool.com/ethw" target="_blank">cruxpool.com</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPS+</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">32</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://solo-ethw.ua-mining.com/" target="_blank">ua-mining.com[SOLO]</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">33</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://ethcore.ru/pool/ethwpool" target="_blank">ethcore.ru</a></td>
			<td>0.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="6">34</td>
			<td rowspan="6"><a href="https://prohashing.com/" target="_blank">prohashing.com</a></td>
			<td>1.99&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>FPPS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>1.49&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>0.99&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">35</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="http://zergpool.com/" target="_blank">zergpool.com</a></td>
			<td>0.5&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PROP</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="4">36</td>
			<td rowspan="4"><a href="https://ethw.yu-tam.contact/" target="_blank">yu-tam.contact</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">37</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://coolpool.top/pool?coin=ethw&amp;type=pplns" target="_blank">coolpool.top</a></td>
			<td>1&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">38</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://solo-ethw.poolbe.eu/" target="_blank">poolbe.eu[SOLO]</a></td>
			<td>0.4&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SOLO</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="right" rowspan="2">39</td>
			<td rowspan="2"><a href="https://pplns-ethw.poolbe.eu/" target="_blank">poolbe.eu</a></td>
			<td>0.4&nbsp;%</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>PPLNS</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="difficulty">Difficulty</h2>

<p>The complexity of the Ethereum PoW network is a problem solved in <a href="/en/articles/mining">mining</a> to find a block. The more miners mine Ethereum PoW, the harder it is to find a block to reward. <a href="https://2miners.com/en/ethw-network-difficulty">Track difficulty</a> here.</p>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is EthereumPoW and how to mine it? In this guide, you will learn about ETHW - a fork of Ethereum for mining on video cards and ASICs]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">How to stake Ethereum 2.0? How much ETH can you earn?</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/eth-staking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to stake Ethereum 2.0? How much ETH can you earn?" /><published>2022-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/eth-staking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/eth-staking/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper wallet">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      Is Ethereum Staking Profitable?
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>In this beginner’s guide, you will learn all the details about Ethereum staking and which crypto exchanges and pools support it.</em></p>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="notice--info">The process <a href="/en/guide/merge/">updating Ethereum Merge or Ethereum 2.0</a> describes the transition of ETH to a new algorithm. New blockchain blocks can no longer be mined. They are created under a special staking contract.</p>

<p>Simply put, staking is a bank deposit with interest. The user transfers funds to the account, stores them and receives passive income for this. The more funds in the account, the higher the earnings. However, the more participants, the less income.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/eth_21.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/eth_21.png" alt="eth_staking" /> </a></p>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Let’s briefly summarize the main definitions in order to become an expert in this and choose the least risky way to stake:</p>

<dl>
  <dt>Staking<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></dt>
  <dd>this is the placement of crypto-tokens used in the process of mining new coins. As a user, you keep your crypto tokens but assign them to a staking node that takes part in verifying transactions on the network. You become a validator.</dd>
  <dt>Validators<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></dt>
  <dd>these are the nodes of the blockchain that support its operation. They are responsible for confirming and verifying transactions, registering them, and adding new blocks. Simply put, validators are cryptocurrency holders with special software installed on a computer (node).</dd>
  <dt>Nodes (nodes)<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></dt>
  <dd>These are the computers running the program (e.g. Ethereum wallet). Nodes are connected to other computers (with the same software installed) to create a cryptocurrency network.</dd>
</dl>

<h2 id="good-and-bad-ways-risks">Good and bad ways, risks</h2>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/methods.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/methods.png" alt="methods" /> </a></p>

<p>There are 4 ways to start staking:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Solo staking (on your PC). <span class="green">Safe</span> because you are in control of your funds. But <span class="red">it’s not easy</span> to set up your own node. You do not share rewards with other services.</li>
  <li>Staking as a service. <span class="yel">Relatively safe</span>. You need to trust the third-party node operator and pay a percentage for the service. The average difficulty of setting up is because the node is already set up by the service operator.</li>
  <li>Staking in the pool. <span class="yel">Relatively safe</span>. You need to trust the owners of a third-party pool and give a percentage to the pool operator. However, you can place less than 32 coins.</li>
  <li>Staking on exchanges. <span class="red">Not safe</span>. Exchanges are often hacked. Also, exchanges can freeze funds. You can place less than 32 coins. Extremely easy to set up.</li>
</ol>

<p>When we have dealt with the main theses, we can move on to practice. But first, let’s look at profitability.</p>

<h2 id="yield">Yield</h2>

<p>Profitability can be found on the official website of Ethereum<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CURRENT APR</code> means annual income as a percentage.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/rewards.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/rewards.png" alt="rewards" /> </a></p>

<p>It is profitable to engage in staking or not is determined by the number of coins participating in the validation - the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">TOTAL ETH STAKED</code> indicator. In simple terms, income depends on how many stakers deposit 32 ETH. This determines the possible commission that the validator receives.</p>

<h3 id="calculation-example">Calculation example</h3>

<p>Let’s calculate how much profit staking brings in ETH 2.0.</p>

<p class="notice--ya">If only 1 million ETH is staked, then you will be rewarded with approximately 5.76 ETH per year (corresponding to a yield of 18.1%).
But if 30 million ETH participate in the validation, then the income will be about 1 ETH (3.3%) per year.</p>

<p>In total, if about one million ETH users confirm the validation, the annual income will be about 18.1%, and with 30 million ETH - only 3.3%.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/stakefish.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/stakefish.png" alt="stakefish" /> </a></p>

<p>Since actual returns depend on the factors mentioned above, they will also vary greatly in the coming months. However, profits of 3 to 7 percent of ETH can be expected.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">It is also important to know that it is not yet possible to withdraw your deposits or profits. This will only be possible after the <a href="/en/guide/merge/">full implementation of Ethereum 2.0</a>, which is not expected before the end of 2022.</p>

<h3 id="calculators">Calculators</h3>

<p>There are various calculators on the Internet that show the possible profitability.</p>

<p class="notice--success">List of online calculators:<br />
<i class="fa fa-calculator"></i> <a href="https://www.stakingrewards.com/earn/ethereum-2-0/">stakingrewards.com</a><br />
<i class="fa fa-calculator"></i> <a href="https://beaconscan.com/staking-calculator">beaconscan.com</a><br />
<i class="fa fa-calculator"></i> <a href="https://ethereumprice.org/eth-2-calculator/">ethereumprice.org</a><br />
<i class="fa fa-calculator"></i> <a href="https://ethscan.org/calculator">ethscan.org</a><br />
<i class="fa fa-calculator"></i> <a href="https://walletburst.com/tools/ethereum-staking-calculator/">walletburst.com</a></p>

<p>Calculate how much you can earn. The results vary depending on the selected amount, term and type of bets.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/stakingrewards.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/stakingrewards.png" alt="stakingrewards" /> </a></p>

<h2 id="hardware-requirements">Hardware requirements</h2>

<p>A basic PC with low energy costs is all you need to cut costs and maximize revenue. No need to buy expensive hardware.</p>

<p>According to Prysmatic Labs<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>, the minimum requirements are:</p>

<p class="notice--primary">Memory: 4GB RAM.<br />
Storage: 20 GB free space on SSD.<br />
OS: Linux, Mac OS X 10.14+ or Windows. 64 bit.<br />
Processor: Intel Core i5-760, AMD FX-8100 or better.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Stable internet connection. Your computer must be online 24/7<sup id="fnref:6" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote" rel="footnote">6</a></sup>.</li>
  <li>Ethereum validator requires 32 Ethereum. However, there are other ways that require less ETH to participate in the staking process.</li>
</ul>

<p>Above we wrote about 4 possible ways of staking. Let’s consider them all. Let’s start with the simplest - staking on the exchange.</p>

<section id="how-to-start" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowTo">
<h2 itemprop="name" id="How to stake Ethereum 2.0?">How to stake Ethereum 2.0?</h2>
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step1" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="#step1" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
		<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="1. Register on the exchange or any other service">1. Register on the exchange or any other service</h3>
		<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">

<p>In order to stake, you must first register with an Ethereum trading platform. This can be done using <a href="https://cutt.ly/ECSoMux">website registration form</a>. Fill out the registration form with your email address and a secure password.</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/exchanges/binance/signup.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/exchanges/binance/signup.png" alt=" signup" /> <figcaption>Sign up.</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>You will also need to agree to the terms of service and privacy policy. The account will then be activated by verifying the link you receive in your email.</p>
<p>The platform requires identity verification. If you don't want to upload your documents then <a href="https://cutt.ly/YCD68yn">register on the AAX platform</a>.</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/exchanges/aax/signup.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/exchanges/aax/signup.png" alt=" signup" /> <figcaption>Sign up.</figcaption></a></figure>

		</div>
	</div>
	
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step2" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="#step2" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
		<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="2. Fund your trading account">2. Fund your trading account</h3>
		<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">
		<div>
<p>Next, you need to replenish your account. With most of the providers we recommend, deposits are free and can be made using the usual methods - credit cards, SEPA transfers, instant transfers and e-wallets.</p>

<p>However, before doing this, you need to know how much fiat currency or other cryptocurrencies you will need to purchase the equivalent amount of Ethereum. This way you calculate the amount of the deposit.</p>
<a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/calc.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/calc.png" alt="calc" /> </a>
<p class="notice--primary">To do this, we recommend that you use the <a href="https://ethereumprice.org/eth-2-calculator/">Ethereum 2.0 rate calculator</a>. It can be used to calculate income depending on the number of staked tokens.</p>
	
</div>
</div>
	</div>
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step3" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="/#step3" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.jpg" />
	<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="3. Transfer ETH to a staking wallet">3. Transfer ETH to a staking wallet</h3>
	<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">
<p>To do this, open the "Earn" tab and select <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/eth2">ETH 2.0</a>. After that, click "Stake now" and you will be able to participate.</p>
<a href="/assets/images/exchanges/binance/en/staking.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/exchanges/binance/en/staking.png" alt="staking" /> </a>
<p>The platform will credit you with BETH, a tokenized asset that represents your ETH in staking at a ratio of 1:1. Binance will credit BETH to your spot account.</p>
<p>After completing the first stage, you can exchange your BETH for ETH at a ratio of 1:1 and receive an amount equal to the current amount of BETH with interest.</p>

	</div>
	</div>
<div class="panel panel-default" id="videoguide" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="/#videoguide" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
	<div class="panel-body">
	<meta itemprop="text" content="How to Staking on Binance. ETH 2.0 - Beginner's Guide" />
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT13M11S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-08-12T15:34:32Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/XJzDZWJYhlQ/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="2798" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/XJzDZWJYhlQ" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="XJzDZWJYhlQ"></div>
<div itemprop="description">
<p>Staking is extremely simple. It's just 2 steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Step 1: You stake Ethereum on Binance</li>
<li>Step 2: You'll earn more ETH every day automatically. And as you've seen on my previous videos, I've made a lot of money by staking on Binance and you have been absolutely loving it.</li>
</ol>
<p>in this video I'll give you the pros &amp; cons of staking Ethereum on Binance and cryptocurrency staking in general. Some people only give you the benefits. Some people give you only about the risks. I'll show you both.</p>
<p class="notice--success">You'll also learn about the <a href="/en/guide/merge/">ETH 2.0 Merge</a> that is about to happen soon and what does it mean for Ethereum.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>

<p>Other staking methods include services such as DeFi.</p>

<h2 id="defi-and-services">DeFi and services</h2>

<p><dfn>DeFi</dfn> are traditional financial instruments built on the blockchain, in particular on Ethereum<sup id="fnref:7" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote" rel="footnote">7</a></sup>.</p>

<p>If you already have your own wallet and store some of your coins on MetaMask, for example, then you have the option of staking Ethereum through DeFi providers.</p>

<p class="notice--warning">The most famous example is <a href="https://lido.fi/">Lido Finance</a>.</p>

<p>The DeFi provider allows you to stake Ethereum as easily as possible without neglecting the idea of ​​decentralization.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Where to stake ETH? Ethereum Crypto Passive Income (Coinbase, Kucoin, Binance)</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT19M12S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2021-09-16T18:30:15Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/SdwtOes8LDQ/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="40265" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/SdwtOes8LDQ" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="SdwtOes8LDQ"></div>
<div itemprop="description"><p>How to get crypto dividends by just owning any amount of Ethereum. In this video I show you how to stake your ethereum 2.0 to make crypto passive income.</p>
</div>
</div>

<h2 id="pools">Pools</h2>

<p>Pooling involves staking through centralized online brokers.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/pools.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/pools.png" alt="pools" /> </a></p>

<p>The largest pools include the following list:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Lido</li>
  <li>Coinbase</li>
  <li>Kraken</li>
  <li>Binance</li>
  <li>Staked.us</li>
  <li>Whale 0x5d7</li>
  <li>Bitcoin suisse</li>
  <li>Stakefish</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/pools_1.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/pools_1.png" alt="pools_1" /> </a></p>

<p>However, to work in some pools, you will need to deposit 32 ETH. Others work with a deposit of 0.01 ETH</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/pools_2.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/en/pools_2.png" alt="pools_2" /> </a></p>

<p class="notice--primary">For a complete list of pools, visit <a href="https://beaconcha.in/pools">beaconcha.in</a>.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Lido Staking Tutorial (ETH, Solana, Matic) - For Beginners</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT13M24S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-03-21T18:28:17Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bGLyFXXvCWI/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="12246" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/bGLyFXXvCWI" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="bGLyFXXvCWI"></div>
<span itemprop="description">In this video, we cover what Lido Finance is, how to stake ETH, SOL, MATIC etc.</span>
</div>

<h2 id="launching-a-node-on-its-own">Launching a node on its own</h2>

<p>If you have 32 ETH, you can also participate in block validation yourself. However, for this you need a special “<a href="https://academy.binance.com/en/articles/custodial-vs-non-custodial-wallets-what-s-the-difference">non-custodial wallet</a>”.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">Such a system is too complicated for beginners, and investments become too risky. Also, unless you hold a significant amount of ETH, the chances of finding a block to validate are extremely low. Given all these nuances, in the following articles, we will look at running a node on its own.</p>

<p>So don’t forget to bookmark miningsoft.org!</p>

<h2 id="risks">Risks</h2>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/eth_9.jpg" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/eth_9.jpg" alt="eth_9" /> </a></p>

<p>As mentioned earlier, the validator requires unrestricted network availability to work. On exchanges and some services, ETH must be stored in a <a href="https://bytwork.com/articles/kholodnyy-goryachiy-koshelek">hot wallet</a>, as proof of ownership must be provided over the Internet at any time.</p>

<p class="notice--warning">This is considered a potential risk for attacks. The validator undertakes to store coins from several months to several years. If the price rises or falls, validators will not be able to access their deposit and sell ETH.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/hack_2.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/hack_2.png" alt="hack" /> </a></p>

<p class="notice--ya">In the event of a sharp drop in price, the commission received will no longer be able to compensate for any losses, so staking turns into a loss-making business.</p>

<p>In addition to the potential loss due to a temporary price drop, there is also the risk of losing a depositdue to breaking the rules.</p>

<p>Validators who do not follow the rules can be fined<sup id="fnref:8" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote" rel="footnote">8</a></sup>. Staking Ethereum 2.0 has 2 potential penalties:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Reward reduction.</li>
  <li>Partial loss of the deposit.</li>
</ol>

<p>The reduction of remuneration occurs even with minor violations. For example, if it is impossible to connect to the validator over the network. Partial loss of the deposit usually threatens only in case of serious violations.</p>

<p>These risks include the constant generation of “bad” blocks or careless duplication of transactions.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/hack.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/hack.png" alt="hack" /> </a></p>

<p>Moreover, there is another danger, mainly at the initial stage of Ethereum 2.0. There is no absolute certainty that new protocols will be secure, error-free and hacker-proof smart contracts.</p>

<p>To minimize this risk, the developers of the Ethereum Foundation reviewed their code several times with experts. Important components also went through an extensive testing phase.</p>

<h2 id="pros-and-cons">Pros and cons</h2>

<p>It’s time to decide if staking is good or bad?</p>

<div class="notice--success">
  <p><i class="fa fa-check-circle"></i> <b>Benefits</b>:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Remuneration - from 3% to 15% per annum</li>
    <li>Ideal for long-term HODL strategies<sup id="fnref:9" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:9" class="footnote" rel="footnote">9</a></sup></li>
    <li>You can start with a small deposit</li>
  </ul>
</div>

<div class="notice--danger">
  <p><i class="fa fa-times-circle"></i> <b>Risks</b>:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Not an easy process, especially launching your own node</li>
    <li>Network fines</li>
    <li>The need to trust third parties if staking goes through exchanges</li>
  </ul>

</div>

<h2 id="frequently-asked-questions">Frequently asked Questions</h2>

<div class="schema-faq-code" itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/FAQPage">
    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Where does the income come from?">Where does the income come from?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Validators collect fees from those who make transactions on the blockchain. </p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="How much can I earn?">How much can I earn?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">As with any investment, staking offers the prospect of profit. However, it always depends on the crypto broker you end up choosing.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="How many coins do you need?">How many coins do you need?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">The volume depends on the service. Depending on the online broker, you can stake with a minimum of 0.1 ETH.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Can I withdraw staked ETH?">Can I withdraw staked ETH?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Depending on the provider, you can withdraw ETH from staking, but then you will have to expect the rewards to be lost.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Can I lose staked ETH?">Can I lose staked ETH?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Yes you can. Due to network errors, hacks and exchange scams.</p>
        </div>
    </div>
	<div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="How long will ETH be staked?">How long will ETH be staked?</h3>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">
You will not be able to withdraw and exchange the rewards you earn through staking until the Ethereum 2.0 upgrade is completed. It should take place at the end of 2022 and end at the beginning of 2023.</p>
         </div>
     </div>
</div>

<h2 id="should-i-stake">Should I stake?</h2>

<p>Investing in staking may be suitable for those investors who are looking for a reasonable investment strategy for the medium to long term. These investors can benefit from good returns comparable to dividends.</p>

<p>For this type of investment, as for most others, a positive change in the price of the asset is a prerequisite for making a profit. However, you also need to take the risks that a token price drop can cause.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/eth_10.webp" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/eth_staking/eth_10.webp" alt="eth_10" /> </a></p>

<p>Opinion of the coindesk platform:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Standing up nodes in multiples of 32 ETH and running them with barely any downtime while the assets are locked up for what could be years won’t be for everyone – and it shouldn’t be.<sup id="fnref:10" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:10" class="footnote" rel="footnote">10</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>On the other hand, traders whothose more focused on day trading or swing trading will not find it particularly advantageous to hold coins for an unpredictable period of time. Your profit is mainly determined by short-term price fluctuations.</p>

<p class="notice--success">However, staking is a reflection of the true evolution in the blockchain network. Don’t you want to be a part of it and benefit at the same time?</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">The TRUTH About Ethereum Staking Rewards...EARN Passive Income?</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT5M41S" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-10-25T19:00:19Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/x4ias6jV-lI/default.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="24430" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/x4ias6jV-lI" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="x4ias6jV-lI"></div>
<span itemprop="description">A lot of people are saying ETH is due for a dump after the move to POS, but not only do I believe this to be untrue, I believe there is solid passive income to be made. In this video I give you the truth on Ethereum staking nodes, how they work, and what they mean for Ethereum and the crypto landscape as a whole.  </span>
</div>

<p>Thus, staking is always useful if you want to invest small amounts in a promising investment.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learn/crypto-basics/what-is-staking">What is staking</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.pcmag.com/encyclopedia/term/blockchain-validator">blockchain validator</a> <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/what-is-a-node/">What Is a Node?</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://ethereum.org/en/staking/">Ethereum Staking Profitability - ethereum.org</a> <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://medium.com/prysmatic-labs/introducing-topaz-testnet-8e8a4e00a700">System Requirements</a> <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:6" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://kb.beaconcha.in/staking-and-hardware">Staking and Hardware - Ethereum Knowledge Base 2.0</a> <a href="#fnref:6" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:7" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/decentralized-finance-defi-5113835">What is DeFi (Ethereum) in cryptocurrency? (Decentralization Finance)</a> <a href="#fnref:7" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:8" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://notes.ethereum.org/@vbuterin/serenity_design_rationale">Slashing and anti-correlation penalties</a> <a href="#fnref:8" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:9" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hodl">What is Hodl</a> <a href="#fnref:9" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:10" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/tech/2020/11/06/to-stake-or-no-thats-the-eth-20-question/">To Stake or No? That’s the Eth 2.0 Question</a> <a href="#fnref:10" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is Ethereum Staking Profitable? In this beginner’s guide, you will learn all the details about Ethereum staking and which crypto exchanges and pools support it.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Ethereum 2.0 Merge Fork Explained: launch Date and Mining</title><link href="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/merge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethereum 2.0 Merge Fork Explained: launch Date and Mining" /><published>2022-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/merge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://miningsoft.org/ru/guide/merge/"><![CDATA[<div class="paper amd">
  <div class="pattern">
    <div class="note-cont">
      Yes, Ethereum 2.0 kill mining. But there will be new opportunities.
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p><em>Exploring Ethereum 2.0 - The Benefits, Mining and Launch Date</em></p>

<script async="" src="https://coinzillatag.com/lib/display.js"></script>

<div class="coinzilla" data-zone="C-26960aca952082b4725"></div>
<script>
    window.coinzilla_display = window.coinzilla_display || [];
    var c_display_preferences = {};
    c_display_preferences.zone = "26960aca952082b4725";
    c_display_preferences.width = "300";
    c_display_preferences.height = "250";
    coinzilla_display.push(c_display_preferences);
</script>

<h2 id="ethereum-20-update">Ethereum 2.0 update</h2>

<p class="notice--danger">When we talk about Ethereum 2.0 or ETH2, there is a key element that characterizes this upgrade. Blockchain said goodbye to ETH mining and implemented on <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking">ETH staking</a>.</p>

<p>Ethereum 2.0 has undergone changes - now it is called Ethereum Merge. The process of transition from the old algorithm to the new one is called “fusion”, a fork of the cryptocurrency. There are two independent Ethereum blockchains:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Proof of Work (PoW) - used <em>before</em> the fork</li>
  <li>Proof of Stake (PoS) - used <em>after</em> a fork</li>
</ol>

<div class="imgcen">
<iframe class="your-ad-position-style" src="https://mat.cryptox-ads.io/cxAdsAssets/banner-basic-v0.11/index.html?size=300*250&amp;app_id=10905748&amp;placement_id=20003615" loading="lazy" style="border:0;width:300px; height:250px"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Let’s briefly recap the basic concepts to move on:</p>

<dl>
  <dt>Proof of Work<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></dt>
  <dd>An algorithm that allows you to engage in mining, i.e. ensure the operation of the cryptocurrency network using equipment (video cards, ASICs, etc.). This algorithm has been criticized - it uses a lot of electricity, pollutes the environment, etc. Literally: “proof of work” means proof of operation of the equipment.</dd>
  <dt>Proof of Stake<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></dt>
  <dd>An algorithm that allows you to engage in staking - receiving rewards for owning cryptocurrency. When <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking/">staking cryptocurrencies</a>, you earn funds by storing coins or tokens in your wallet. You need to make a contribution for a fixed period of time. Literally: “proof of ownership”.</dd>
  <dt>The Merge</dt>
  <dd>The process of merging the current Ethereum mainnet with the Proof of Stake system (<a href="https://ethereum.org/en/upgrades/beacon-chain/">Beacon Chain</a>).<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></dd>
</dl>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/pow_vs_pos2.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/pow_vs_pos2.png" alt="pow_vs_pos" /> <figcaption>mining 1.0 vs 2.0 staking.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>In summary, Proof of Work (System 1.0) is a legacy consensus mechanism that allows Ethereum to be mined on GPUs. Proof of Stake is a new mechanism that will allow you to “mine” <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking/">Ethereum using staking</a> - receiving passive income from placing your assets.</p>

<h2 id="ethereum-vs-ethereum-20">Ethereum vs Ethereum 2.0</h2>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/consumption.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/consumption.png" alt=" consumption" /> <figcaption>Ethereum Energy Consumption Index.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>There are the following differences between the two networks:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Efficiency - Ethereum will become 99.95% more energy efficient. It is estimated that 77.53 TWh will no longer be required to secure the network with Proof of Stake. This is the power consumption of the whole country - Chile.<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup><sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></li>
  <li>Sharding<sup id="fnref:6" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote" rel="footnote">6</a></sup> - the network will be divided into 18 “shards” working simultaneously. This will dramatically increase the speed of work.</li>
  <li>Staking<sup id="fnref:7" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote" rel="footnote">7</a></sup> - Ethereum will switch to a Proof-of-Stake consensus, where everyone can stake assets and help protect the network, earning on it.</li>
  <li>Safety. Network discrediting will become much more expensive when using Proof-of-Stake. This will reduce the chance of a <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/1/51-attack.asp">51% attack</a></li>
</ol>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/pos.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/pos.png" alt="pos" /> </a></p>

<p>Ethereum 2.0 is an update to the Ethereum blockchain protocol that has already been partially implemented. Ethereum 2.0, now called the “consensus layer”, has been in development for several years.</p>

<p class="notice--danger">In Blockchain 2.0, the resource-intensive method of mining should give way to the so-called <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking/">staking method</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>In Ethereum 1.0, transactions are verified by solving cryptographic arithmetic problems. For example, the higher the price of Ethereum, the greater the incentive to participate in the mining process. And the more miners involved, the higher the power consumption.</li>
  <li>Ethereum 2.0 implemented “Proof of Stake”. This means that those with the most electrical power no longer determine the future of the network. You will be more likely to be selected as a “validator” due to the random mechanism.</li>
</ul>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/btc_vs_eth.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/btc_vs_eth.png" alt="btc_vs_eth" /><figcaption>BTC vs ETH.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Unlike Bitcoin, when using the Proof of Stake approach, the network accordingly uses fewer resources, but is also less decentralized.</p>

<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Ethereum Mainnet Merge Viewing Party</span>
<meta itemprop="duration" content="P0D" />
<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-09-02T13:02:29Z" />
<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Nx-jYgI0QVI/default_live.jpg" />
<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="57943" />
<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/Nx-jYgI0QVI" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="Nx-jYgI0QVI"></div>
<span itemprop="description">Join Bankless, EthStaker, Ethereum Cat Herders, The Daily Gwei, along with many notable guests and the wider Ethereum community as we celebrate the Ethereum network transition from Proof-of-Work to Proof-of-Stake!</span>
</div>

<h2 id="upgrade-dates">Upgrade Dates</h2>

<p>Ethereum 2.0 will be launched in 3 phases with the following dates:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Phase 0 - launch of the Beacon Chain network (launched 12/01/2020)</li>
  <li>Phase 1 - Merge (completed at 09/15/2022 9:42 AM).</li>
  <li>Phase 2 - Sharding (follows after the first phase).</li>
</ol>

<p><a href="https://ethereum.org/en/upgrades/beacon-chain/">Beacon Chain</a> (formerly known as “Eth2”) is live now. This consensus layer already exists as a separate chain from the existing mainnet (i.e. the “run layer” formerly known as “Eth1”).</p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/history.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/history.png" alt="history" /> </a></p>

<p class="notice--danger">The current POW algorithm replaced by a consensus POS protocol on the Beacon Chain network. Therefore, this stage is known as “Merge”. This will also stopped the use of Ethereum mining.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/nomining.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/nomining.png" alt=" nomining" /> <figcaption>The end of the era of ETH mining.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The Ethereum merge was completed on 09/15/2022 at 9:42 am.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">And we finalized!<br /><br />Happy merge all. This is a big moment for the Ethereum ecosystem. Everyone who helped make the merge happen should feel very proud today.</p>&mdash; vitalik.eth (@VitalikButerin) <a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1570306185391378434?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2022</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p class="notice--ya">However, such a comprehensive change cannot occur on a single key date. Accordingly, the developers decided to divide this change into several phases.</p>

<p>The transition is expected to continue until 2023. However, with the update, developers are addressing two fundamental blockchain problems:</p>
<ul>
  <li>High energy consumption for mining</li>
  <li>Problems with scaling due to the small number of transactions.</li>
</ul>

<section id="how-to-start" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowTo">
<h2 itemprop="name" id="How it works and why it matters?">How it works and why it matters?</h2>
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step1" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="#step1" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
		<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="1. Внесите депозит в 32 ETH для запуска стейкинга">1. Deposit 32 ETH to start staking</h3>
		<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">
<p>To maintain the network and generate income, it is required to purchase a certain amount of cryptocurrency necessary for staking.</p>
<p class="notice--ya">Main Article: <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking/">Staking Ethereum 2.0</a></p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step2" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="#step2" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
		<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="2. Become a network validator">2. Become a network validator</h3>
		<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">
		<div>
<p>Staking freezes your crypto assets and pays interest for maintaining the security of the network. You become a validator.</p>
<p class="notice--success">The ETH 2.0 network chooses which participant validates the next block based on how many coins are staked by the validator.
</p>
<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/pos_2.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/pos_2.png" alt="pos_2" /> <figcaption>Simplified ETH 2.0 workflow.</figcaption></a></figure>

		</div>
		</div>
	</div>
	<div class="panel panel-default" id="step3" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="/#step3" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.jpg" />
	<h3 class="panel-title" itemprop="name" id="3. Earn income by protecting the network">3. Earn income by protecting the network</h3>
	<div class="panel-body" itemprop="text">
<p>To maintain the network in Ethereum 2.0, an incentive was invented - the payment of interest for the placement of their assets. Stakers stake assets to validate a new block on the blockchain network. If the block is in error, then the staked amount will be "cut". If the block is valid (correct), then the staker will receive back staked assets and an additional reward.</p>

	</div>
	</div>
<div class="panel panel-default" id="videoguide" itemprop="step" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/HowToStep">
	<link itemprop="url" href="/#videoguide" />
	<meta itemprop="image" content="/assets/images/og.png" />
	<div class="panel-body">
	<meta itemprop="text" content="Ethereum Merge Release: roadmap, beacon chain and benefits (Explained)" />
<div itemprop="video" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/VideoObject">
<span itemprop="name" class="bold">Ethereum Merge Release: roadmap, beacon chain and benefits (Explained)</span>
	<meta itemprop="duration" content="PT16M9S" />
	<meta itemprop="uploadDate" content="2022-08-03T18:03:26Z" />
	<meta itemprop="thumbnailURL" content="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/EEuPmA8w0Kc/default.jpg" />
	<meta itemprop="interactionCount" content="155012" />
	<meta itemprop="embedURL" content="https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/EEuPmA8w0Kc" />
<div class="youtube-player" data-id="EEuPmA8w0Kc"></div>
	<span itemprop="description">What is the Ethereum Merge? What are its economic implications? And what are the main merge risks and misconceptions? You’ll find answers to these questions and more in this video.</span>
  </div>
</div>
</div>
</section>

<h2 id="what-is-ethereum-20---merge-and-why-is-it-good">What is Ethereum 2.0 - “Merge” and why is it good?</h2>

<p>ETH 2.0 is by no means a new cryptocurrency. Technically speaking, this is not even a hard fork, as it was when two different cryptocurrencies appeared as a result - Ethereum and <a href="https://bytwork.com/en/articles/how-buy-ethereum-classic">Ethereum Classic (ETC)</a>.</p>

<p>Since the term Ethereum 2.0 or Eth2/Eth 2.0 prevails, in this article we will stick to this terminology.</p>

<p>Instead of a new coin, Eth 2.0 describes a series of upgrades to the previous version of Ethereum.</p>

<p class="notice--primary"><i class="fab fa-ethereum"></i> The official name of Ethereum 2 is Serenity<sup id="fnref:8" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote" rel="footnote">8</a></sup>.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/update.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/update.png" alt="update" /> <figcaption>Network updates.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>This update is good because it brings 3 key features:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Increased network efficiency</li>
  <li>Increased throughput</li>
  <li>Increased network security</li>
</ol>

<p>Thus, Eth 2.0 is a description of numerous updates. Therefore, it is important that we take a look at the classic Ethereum that we are familiar with. Then we can understand why this update is happening at all.</p>

<p class="notice--info">Ethereum was created as a platform for <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/decentralized-applications-dapps.asp">decentralized applications (dApps)</a>. Using <a href="https://www.ibm.com/topics/smart-contracts">smart contracts</a>, developers can build applications on the Ethereum blockchain.</p>

<p>Since these applications depend on a functioning and efficient blockchain of the platform being used, Ethereum vulnerabilities could lead developers to port their decentralized applications to other ecosystems.</p>

<p>Next, we will talk about exactly which vulnerabilities are involved and why upgrading to Ethereum 2 is so important. And also about the refusal of mining.</p>

<h2 id="ethereum-mining-going-away">Ethereum mining going away</h2>

<p>Bitcoin and Ethereum, the two largest blockchains on the market, have one thing in common - the Proof of Work algorithm. In other words, mining. And this algorithm has a fundamental drawback - mining requires computing power.</p>

<p>A high level of performance requires appropriate energy.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/footprints_1.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/footprints_1.png" alt=" footprints_1" /> <figcaption>Annual CO₂ emissions according to @digiconomist.ne</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The data shows that annual CO₂ emissions alone are 45 megatons, equivalent to all of Hong Kong’s annual emissions.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/footprints_2.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/en/footprints_2.png" alt=" footprints_2" /> <figcaption>Transaction costs according to @digiconomist.ne</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--danger">The network’s annual energy demand is 80.95 TWh. This corresponds to the electricity needed by a US household in 7.03 days.</p>

<p>But the impact on the environment does not end there, because kilotons of electronic waste (video cards, electronic components) are generated annually.</p>

<p>PoW is extremely energy intensive and is no longer in the current “spirit of the age”. The solution is the end of mining and the beginning of the POS era.</p>

<p>Accordingly, the energy-intensive proof-of-work algorithm is replaced by the energy-efficient proof-of-stake algorithm.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/2.0.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/2.0.png" alt=" 2.0" /> <figcaption>Blockchain will stop GPU mining.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p class="notice--primary">On the other hand, sharding is also considered one of the current upgrades. It can be assumed that the Ethereum blockchain in the form in which it exists today will subsequently cease to exist.</p>

<h2 id="gpu-mining-after-the-merge">GPU Mining after the merge</h2>

<p>There is a project claiming to be an Ethereum mining network. <a href="https://github.com/ethereumpow">EthereumPow</a> is the original PoW-based Ethereum network. It is developed by anonymous developers. Looks like they are from China.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/ethw.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/ethw.png" alt=" ethw" /> <figcaption>The @ETHW community on medium.</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>The end of mining is dated September 14-15. The start of ETHW mining will begin with the following blocks:</p>

<div class="language-config highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="n">eth</span>.<span class="n">blockNumber</span>: <span class="m">15471668</span> <span class="n">networkid</span>: <span class="m">0</span><span class="n">x1</span>
<span class="n">eth</span>.<span class="n">blockNumber</span>: <span class="m">15471669</span> <span class="n">networkid</span>: <span class="m">0</span><span class="n">x2711</span>
<span class="n">eth</span>.<span class="n">blockNumber</span>: <span class="m">15471669</span> <span class="n">networkid</span>: <span class="m">0</span><span class="n">x2711</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p class="notice--info">Read more <a href="/en/guide/ethw/">what is ETHPoW (Ethereum PoW) and how to mine it?</a></p>

<p>Whether to trust the EthereumPow (ETHW) project is up to you. This is outside the scope of our study.</p>

<p class="notice--info">Find out more:<br />
<i class="fab fa-medium"></i> <a href="https://medium.com/@ETHW">https://medium.com/@ETHW</a><br />
<i class="fab fa-github"></i> <a href="https://github.com/ethereumpow">https://github.com/ethereumpow</a><br />
<i class="fa fa-globe"></i> <a href="https://ethereumpow.org/">https://ethereumpow.org/</a></p>

<p>There are alternatives to Ethereum mining:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ethereum Classic</li>
  <li>Ergo</li>
  <li>Ravencoin</li>
  <li>neoxa</li>
</ul>

<p class="notice--success">Here you can see the list of <a href="https://bytwork.com/en/articles/ethereum-pos-mayning">coins to mine after the ETH 2.0 merge</a></p>

<h3 id="automatic-change-from-eth-to-etc-for-the-merge">Automatic change from ETH to ETC for the Merge</h3>

<p>Just to do automatic change to ETC when the pool of ETH goes down in the Merge, you need to have <a href="/en/miners/lolminer/">lolMiner</a> 1.57+</p>

<p>It is as easy as add <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">etc:</code> like this in the Extra Config:</p>

<div class="language-config highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>--<span class="n">pool</span> <span class="n">etc</span>:<span class="n">eu1</span>-<span class="n">etc</span>.<span class="n">ethermine</span>.<span class="n">org</span>:<span class="m">4444</span> --<span class="n">user</span> <span class="m">0</span><span class="n">x85Df244a3C8d6442225360bE681B7F7D803c0e78</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><a href="/assets/images/miners/lolminer/etc_hive.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/miners/lolminer/etc_hive.png" alt="etc_hive" /> </a></p>

<p><a href="/assets/images/miners/lolminer/etc_rave.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/miners/lolminer/etc_rave.png" alt="etc_rave" /> </a></p>

<p>That will continue Mining in this case KASPA and continue doing ETC.</p>

<p>It can be used to dual Mine KASPA or ALPH or simple ETC.</p>

<p>In case you want a SSL just add <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ssl://</code> before <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">etc:</code></p>

<div class="language-config highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>--<span class="n">pool</span> <span class="n">ssl</span>://<span class="n">etc</span>:<span class="n">eu1</span>-<span class="n">etc</span>.<span class="n">ethermine</span>.<span class="n">org</span>:<span class="m">4444</span> --<span class="n">user</span> <span class="m">0</span><span class="n">x85Df244a3C8d6442225360bE681B7F7D803c0e78</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="what-should-be-done-during-a-hard-fork">What should be done during a hard fork?</h2>

<p>The good news is that the developers are paying special attention to the update so as not to create difficulties for Ethereum users. This means that you won’t have to actively do anything until the end of the update.</p>

<p>There are different scenarios for existing ETH holders:</p>

<p><i class="fa fa-check-circle"></i> As long as you are simpleIf you hold, trade or use ETH in your applications, there is nothing you need to do. In this case, your deposits will be automatically transferred to Eth2.</p>

<p><i class="fa fa-check-circle"></i> If you want <a href="/en/guide/eth-staking/">to start staking in Ethereum 2.0</a>, you can already participate. It is possible to join staking as a validator at any time as long as you have 32 ETH to deposit.</p>

<p><span class="bold">What to do if there is no 32 ETH?</span></p>

<p class="notice--info">You can start staking on <a href="https://cutt.ly/ECSoMux">Binance exchange</a> from 0.1 ETH.</p>

<figure><a href="/assets/images/guide/merge/pos_3.png" class="image-popup"> <img src="/assets/images/guide/merge/pos_3.png" alt=" pos_3" /> <figcaption>2.0</figcaption></a></figure>

<h2 id="frequently-asked-questions">Frequently asked Questions</h2>

<p>In this section, you will find answers to the most important questions about the Ethereum 2.0 update.</p>

<div class="schema-faq-code" itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/FAQPage">
    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="When will ETH 2.0 be released?">When will ETH 2.0 be released?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">The release of the 2.0 version took place on September 15, 2022 at 9:42 am (GMT+3).</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="How much will Ethereum 2.0 cost?">How much will Ethereum 2.0 cost?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">According to DigitalCoinPrice analysts, by 2023 ETH could cost an average of $2,274.64. </p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="What is Ethereum 2.0?">What is Ethereum 2.0?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">ETH2 describes a series of updates to the Ethereum platform and its associated cryptocurrency, Ether (ETH). It includes staking, sharding and proof of stake.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

	<div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
         <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="What has changed since Eth 2.0?">What has changed since Eth 2.0?</h3>
         <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
              <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Ethereum 2.0 has changed the way transactions are processed and new coins are created. The project changed the algorithm from "proof of work" to "proof of stake".</p>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Why do we need Ethereum 2.0?">Why do we need Ethereum 2.0?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">The Ethereum network can no longer handle the load of transactions efficiently. This results in outrageously high commissions. The developers hope this change will lead to faster transactions, lower fees, and a better environmental balance.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Where to buy Ethereum 2.0?">Where to buy Ethereum 2.0?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Because this is not a new cryptocurrency, you can “buy” Eth 2.0 anywhere you can buy Ethereum. However, while the upgrade is still pending, some crypto exchanges are offering the opportunity to benefit from staking Eth 2.0 right now. Therefore, some exchanges will show you Ethereum and Ethereum 2.0. On the exchanges, your coins will be blocked until the update is completed. Of course, you can also move your ETH to ETH 2.0 by staking yourself.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Is Ethereum 2.0 a new coin?">Is Ethereum 2.0 a new coin?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Ethereum 2.0 is not a new coin and will not change the amount of original ETH you own.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Will I get an airdrop when I fork?">Will I get an airdrop when I fork?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">A fork has been announced that will remain on Proof of Work. This fork creates another coin (ETHW). Any address that previously had ETH will subsequently have ETHW. </p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="How much are ETHW coins worth?">How much are ETHW coins worth?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">This new coin is currently traded in futures. You can see the current price on <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/ethereum-pow-on-poloniex">Poloniex</a>.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Will I receive coins automatically on Ledger?">Will I receive coins automatically on Ledger?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Yes. However, new coins must also be supported by the wallet software in order to be able to access them. But most likely with a few settings it will be easy to access these coins</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="And if the coins are on the exchange?">And if the coins are on the exchange?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Further it all depends on whether the exchange supports new ETHW coins or not. Almost all major exchanges have announced that they will be giving away fork coins.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

<div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Will I get a fork if I stake?">Will I get a fork if I stake?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">No. Staking coins have no value in the PoW chain.</p>
        </div>
    </div>
<div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="What will happen to mining?">What will happen to mining?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">We believe in mining and will continue to look for new opportunities. Several mining hard forks have already been announced. Mining has proven its viability for years. </p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="How to prepare for POS?">How to prepare for POS?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Update your hardware wallets beforehand.
If you keep funds on exchanges, then you do not need to do anything.
</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="What will happen to ETH payouts from pools?">What will happen to ETH payouts from pools?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Each mining pool provides payout information on their website. Make sure you have time to withdraw funds to your wallet.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="What to mine after POS?">What to mine after POS?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">There are more than enough cryptocurrencies for mining after the transition of Ethereum to the new consensus algorithm.
All of them are listed in <a href="https://bytwork.com/en/articles/ethereum-pos-mayning">detailed material on the bytwork.com portal</a>.</p>
        </div>
    </div>

    <div itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntity" itemtype="https://schema.org/Question" class="faq-question">
        <h3 itemprop="name" class="faq-q" id="Where to store Ethereum after switching to POS?">Where to store Ethereum after switching to POS?</h3>
        <div itemscope="" itemprop="acceptedAnswer" itemtype="https://schema.org/Answer">
             <p itemprop="text" class="faq-a">Use only official wallets for storage. <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/wallets/">List of wallets</a> can be found on the site.</p>
        </div>
    </div>	
</div>
</div>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof_of_work">Proof of work</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof_of_stake">Proof of stake</a> <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://ethereum.org/ru/upgrades/merge/">The Merge</a> <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://ethereum.org/en/energy-consumption/#introduction">Ethereum energy consumption</a> <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://digiconomist.net/ethereum-energy-consumption/">Ethereum Energy Consumption Index</a> <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:6" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://ethereum.org/en/upgrades/sharding/#what-is-sharding">about sharding</a> <a href="#fnref:6" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:7" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://ethereum.org/en/staking/">about Staking</a> <a href="#fnref:7" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:8" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://consensys.net/blog/blockchain-explained/the-roadmap-to-serenity-2/">The Roadmap to Serenity</a> <a href="#fnref:8" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Matthew Wood</name></author><category term="guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, Ethereum 2.0 kill mining. But there will be new opportunities. Exploring Ethereum 2.0 - The Benefits, Mining and Launch Date]]></summary></entry></feed>